<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Software @ CDH – Annual Reports</title><link>/blog/annual-reports/</link><description>Recent content in Annual Reports on Research Software @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/annual-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Work completed in 2023</title><link>/blog/2024/01/work-completed-in-2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/01/work-completed-in-2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Looking back at 2022 — all Geniza, all the time</title><link>/blog/2023/01/looking-back-at-2022-all-geniza-all-the-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/looking-back-at-2022-all-geniza-all-the-time/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The charts below show the substantial amount of effort dedicated to the Princeton Geniza Project in 2022, with a noticeable spike as we worked to complete our commitments on the project before the charter period ended in October.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also noticeable activity on Startwords to finish publication on issue 3; work on PPA enhancements in August and November/December; and beginning to ramp up work on the Lenape Timetree project in the fall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The small amount of work spent on CDH web and mep-django (codebase for Shakepeare and Company Project) reflect a deliberate effort to minimize the work on those projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: What did we work on in 2021?</title><link>/blog/2023/01/what-did-we-work-on-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/what-did-we-work-on-in-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A belated look back at the work we did in 2021. The substantial effort on CDH web reflects the work to migrate to Wagtail for content management. We completed a substantial amount of work on the Princeton Geniza Project across the whole year, a set of enhancements for PPA in July, and a small amount of work on Startwords to publish issue 2. The work on the derrida-django codebase in the fall was to revise the published datasets and prep the side for archiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2020 so far</title><link>/blog/2020/11/2020-so-far/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/2020-so-far/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Our biggest sustained efforts in 2020 have been on mep-django, leading up to the Shakespeare and Company Project 1.0 release in May and &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, leading up to the October launch of issue 1. We also worked on PEMM in January to migrate and support data entry work, and finished agreed upon commitments to wrap the grant year in July.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>