<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Software @ CDH – 2023</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on Research Software @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/iteration-reports/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Nov 27 - Dec 8, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/12/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/12/11/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The only tasks completed this iteration were a revision to the Simulating Risk hawk/dove game to add more options for neighborhood sizes, and a chore to improve the cdh-ansible repository based on feedback from PUL devops team members after a walkthrough of the codebase. The completed work is smaller due to staff time taken up by a conference and teaching. There is progress to update S&amp;amp;co dependencies (currently awaiting testing) and to implement a full-text corpus export script for PPA (in progress).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 14 - Nov 25, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/11/27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/11/27/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We didn&amp;rsquo;t complete any new features this iteration due to other commitments and the holiday. The only issue closed during this was an ansible chore completed as part of the cdh-ansible overview with members of the PUL devops team. We are continuing work on PPA corpus generation, S&amp;amp;co maintenance, and simulations for Simulating Risk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 30 - Nov 10, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/11/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/11/13/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/11/13/featured_lenapetimetree_footer_hu99848f3e5b1e1c2b9eef7d93918d3958_1663863_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="349"/>
&lt;p>As part of a deadline for demoing the Lenape Timetree project for the Munsee language symposium, we worked on some updates and bugfixes and released an update to the theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Simulating Risk, we continued to refine the hawk/dove simulation and worked on batch run analysis. We also fixed a synchronicity bug identified by a philosopher that we consulted with and started working on adding more configurability to various neighborhoods, which will add more parameters for batch analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/11/13/featured_lenapetimetree_footer.png"
alt="Screenshot of updated timetree site with new footer design."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of updated timetree site with new footer design.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 16 - Oct 27, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/10/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/10/30/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/10/30/featured-simrisk-hawkdovevar_hu4eb5fceb78d111afd8472a22d3b80d9e_408794_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="523"/>
&lt;p>We made progress on refining simulations for Simulating Risk; work included refactoring the code to split out single and variable risk modes, since the parameters were increasingly diverging, improving how the simulations and charts were running in Solara, and adding new charts the hawk/dove variable risk simulation to improve interpretation of the simulation&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/10/30/featured-simrisk-hawkdovevar.png"
alt="Screenshot of Hawk/Dove variable risk model with updated charts"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Hawk/Dove variable risk model with updated charts&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 2 - Oct 13, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/10/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/10/16/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/10/16/featured-simrisk-hawkdove-solara-app_huce6f776158f4f7769c3c549871e41a4c_108976_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="526"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we published Startwords issue 4, made progress on Simulating Risk hawk/dove simulation and a sandbox app. We also supported the work to upgrade the Geniza web application to Solr 9; this included releasing new versions of python libraries (piffle, parasolr) to support this update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/10/16/featured-simrisk-hawkdove-solara-app.png"
alt="Screenshot of the solara app running on the sandbox server, with access to all three simulations (hawk/dove variable risk shown)"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the solara app running on the sandbox server, with access to all three simulations (hawk/dove variable risk shown)&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 19 - Sep 30, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/10/03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/10/03/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed out development on the GeoTaste MVP and finished preparations for publishing issue 4 of Startwords. The timetree project is no longer in active development, but as part of prepping for launch and handoff we split out the code and content into separate repositories and made the timetree theme installable as a Hugo module.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/4/">Startwords issue 4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://shakespeareandco.app/">GeoTaste prototype&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 4 - Sep 15, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/09/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/09/18/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/18/featured_cdhweb_404_hua11e8b3c32a8c7468453b9c6d52902ac_283278_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="494"/>
&lt;p>We worked across a number of different projects as we dealt with some maintenance upgrades,
regularly scheduled work, and some work on PPA that we bumped up in priority due to external deadlines. For development work, we completed &lt;strong>10&lt;/strong> points and closed 26 issues bringing up the rolling velocity slightly to &lt;strong>4.7&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geotaste">GeoTaste&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Continued progress towards closing out the prototype.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="simulating-risk">Simulating Risk&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Completed the initial version of the new Hawk/Dove interactive game, with configurable initial hawk odds parameter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Prepping for publication of issue 4. We implemented the new CJK typeface needed for this issue, and completed work on some of the figures and several small issues that cropped up as we worked on this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-web">CDH web&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed one more bugfix and released a minor update with some fixes and improvements tested the previous iteration. Visible updates include integration of a wagtail code formatting block and revised 404 and 500 error page images.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>PPA was not originally on the schedule, but we bumped up priority on work that was planned for later this fall in order to generate PDFs of Editorial articles. We incorporated a few other small improvements into this update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/18/featured_cdhweb_404.png"
alt="New 404 image for CDH website (view live version)"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>New 404 image for CDH website (view &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/_/">live version&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/18/cdhweb_500.png"
alt="New 500 image for CDH website (view live version)"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>New 500 image for CDH website (view &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/_500/">live version&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/18/ppa-editorial.png"
alt="PPA editorial improvements include editors, DOI, and link to PDF"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>PPA editorial improvements include editors, DOI, and link to PDF&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/18/simrisk-hawkdove.png"
alt="Screenshot of current implementation of Hawk/Dove game for Simulating Risk"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of current implementation of Hawk/Dove game for Simulating Risk&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 22 - Sep 2, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/09/05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/09/05/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/05/featured_geotaste_comparison_hub548abacf01200811a686d66b576f540_7077391_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="419"/>
&lt;p>Our work this iteration was spread across multiple project and included some on-going maintenance work, time-sensitive bug fixes, continuing effort on on-going research projects GeoTaste and Simulating Risk, and preliminary work for Startwords issue 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-updates">project updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="geotaste">GeoTaste&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Numerous issues closed as the project team makes a huge effort to close out the tool-building portion of the work and completed related data work needed for the application.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="simulating-risk">Simulating Risk&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We completed work on new Jupyter/Colab notebooks that allow running simulations interactively in Colab using Mesa&amp;rsquo;s new experimental &lt;code>JupyterViz&lt;/code> interface; because it&amp;rsquo;s experimental, this required some pull requests to update Mesa code to add support for functionality we were already using in the previous Mesa runserver interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We preemptively scheduled editorial improvements that were scheduled for later work on PPA because we needed to generate PDFs of editorial essays that were needed for a promotion file.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other">Other&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We also completed some ansible maintenance thanks to support from PUL, completed testing on some small updates for CDH web, made the Lenape Timetree codebase more citable, and closed out an old design task for Startwords in preparation for development work to support Startwords issue 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/05/featured_geotaste_comparison.png"
alt="Screenshot of GeoTaste showing a filtered comparison view"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of GeoTaste showing a filtered comparison view&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/09/05/geotaste_arrondissement_report.png"
alt="Screenshot of GeoTaste showing a report on statisically different arrondissements"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of GeoTaste showing a report on statisically different arrondissements&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Princeton-CDH/simulating-risk/tree/main/notebooks">Simulating Risk notebooks for running simulations in Colab&lt;/a> (To run, click on one of the simulation notebooks, then open in Colab.)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 7 - Aug 18, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/08/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/08/21/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Work completed in this iteration includes a few small bugfixes for the &lt;strong>CDH website&lt;/strong> and some task cleanup for the &lt;strong>Lenape Timetree&lt;/strong> project, as we prep for a public launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is active work on both &lt;strong>geotaste&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Simulating Risk&lt;/strong>, but due to team member availability no issues were completed in this iteration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 24 - Aug 4, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/08/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/08/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/featured_geotaste_huc96e13bb0fdf14c94c9baa83686ce337_4097083_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="317"/>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re a small team working on multiple projects at once. We made significant progress on the &lt;strong>geotaste&lt;/strong> tool, and work has ramped up in intensity with plans to complete the prototype by the end of August. We also continued making progress on the simulations for the &lt;strong>Simulating Risk&lt;/strong> project, completing a revision to one simulation and a new histogram chart. We also completed some maintenance work on the &lt;strong>CDH website&lt;/strong> to upgrade some dependencies, and released a micro version with those changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/featured_geotaste.png"
alt="Screenshot showing resent progress on the Geotaste mapping tool"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing resent progress on the Geotaste mapping tool&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/simrisk_histogram.png"
alt="Screenshot showing Simulating Risk interactive Mesa display of the &amp;amp;lsquo;Risky Bet&amp;amp;rsquo; simulation in progress with the new histogram chart."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing Simulating Risk interactive Mesa display of the &amp;lsquo;Risky Bet&amp;rsquo; simulation in progress with the new histogram chart.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 10 - Jul 21, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/07/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/07/24/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/07/24/featured_geotaste_screenshot_hue5233fb2def8d1c4e5e7b219252cd47b_804204_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="391"/>
&lt;p>We extended this iteration to three weeks, to account for team members being away for the DH2023 conference and on vacation. Work in the past iteration included Simulating Risk, GeoTaste, and some maintenance. GeoTaste has been an ongoing project, but we are now starting to track work via GitHub issues and include it iteration reporting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In terms of development, we completed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> points and &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> issues for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>11.3&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an open question how to track design moving forward, now that we no longer have a designer on staff and are working on projects with less dependency on design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/07/24/featured_geotaste_screenshot.png"
alt="Screenshot showing the current state of the geotaste mapping and comparison tool"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing the current state of the geotaste mapping and comparison tool&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 29 - Jun 9, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/06/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/06/12/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/06/12/featured-lenapetimetree-desktop-zoom_hu68ec7c5dc3e95b8ddece9ebb814d5866_707649_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="352"/>
&lt;p>We made significant progress on the Lenape Timetree project as we worked
to close out the remaining in-scope features, addressed small bugs that cropped
up as the team worked on final edits, and prepped for a 1.0 release and
a soft launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re starting to ramp up on the Simulating Risk project, and have started implementing
a first simulation, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet closed any issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>11.33&lt;/strong>, based largely on the substantial amount of
work completed on the Lenape Timetree project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work is on-going on the GeoTaste project, but we&amp;rsquo;re still considering how and if to include it in regular iteration reporting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/06/12/featured-lenapetimetree-desktop-zoom.png"
alt="A screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing new desktop zoom feature, for improved accessibility."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>A screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing new desktop zoom feature, for improved accessibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 8 - May 19, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/05/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/05/22/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/22/featured-lenape-dedication_huf7eb539c7032352e9298967ccbee171f_1733668_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="350"/>
&lt;p>We continue to focus on the Lenape project as we push it towards completion and soft-launch. We implemented the dedication on the tree, and also completed several UI cleanup items and other chores.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/22/featured-lenape-dedication.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing the dedication, which was implemented last iteration."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing the dedication, which was implemented last iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 24 - May 5, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/05/08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/05/08/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/featured-lenapetimetree-zoom_hu3d530068d76b4ed70eefd48719096ea6_895554_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="690"/>
&lt;p>As in recent iterations, we again focused almost exclusively on the Lenape Timetree project, and made significant progress, including: finishing zoom functionality for mobile, drawing lines for the tree branches, adding a branch legend to the intro panel, and implementing content page and footer designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/featured-lenapetimetree-zoom.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing zoom functionality on mobile."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing zoom functionality on mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/lenapetimetree-branches-legend.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing drawn lines for branches and branch legend in the introduction panel."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing drawn lines for branches and branch legend in the introduction panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/lenapetimetree-contentpages.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree About page showing content page styles and visual identity."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree About page showing content page styles and visual identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 10 - Apr 21, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/04/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/04/24/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/featured-lenape-timetree-active-tag_huc786050210fdda10bfd2153a5e28147a_503140_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="387"/>
&lt;p>For the second iteration in a row, we were able to focus all of our efforts on the Lenape Timetree project as we work to get it over the finish line, and we made significant progress, completing 27 points and 26 issues across design and development work. On the design side, we finished 18 points and 13 issues for a rolling velocity of 9.7; major efforts included the footer, work on visual identity, and 404 error page designs. On the development side, we closed 9 points and 13 issues, bringing our rolling velocity up to 4. The main functionality completed is a collection of user stories related to tag interactions within the timetree.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/featured-lenape-timetree-active-tag.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project with a tag active, highlighting leaves with that tag and deactivating others"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project with a tag active, highlighting leaves with that tag and deactivating others&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/lenape-mobile-info.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project on mobile showing the info button to redisplay the intro when closed"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project on mobile showing the info button to redisplay the intro when closed&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 27 - Apr 7, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/04/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/04/10/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/10/featured-lenape-timetree-branch-order_hu1309d25c97d49ebdf860bf16651cefd6_539235_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="442"/>
&lt;p>All our effort went towards the Lenape Timetree project as we work to get it over the finish line. There isn&amp;rsquo;t as much visible progress in terms of closed issues as we might hope. Development velocity is &lt;strong>2.3&lt;/strong> with 2 points and 7 issues closed, and design velocity is &lt;strong>7.7&lt;/strong> with 2 issues closed. The development points are low in part to the number of design implementation, which we typically track as chores when they are not easily articulable as user-facing features. We have a large number of issues in progress, which hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to complete early this iteration and get a better estimate of how much work is left.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/10/featured-lenape-timetree-branch-order.png"
alt="Screenshot of the latest developmentversion of the Lenape Timetree, showing the leaves organized and more clearly separated by branch"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the &lt;a href="https://lenape-timetree-dev.onrender.com/">latest developmentversion of the Lenape Timetree&lt;/a>, showing the leaves organized and more clearly separated by branch&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 13 - Mar 24, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/03/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/03/27/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/27/featured-lenape-timetree-visual-debug_hue534a4a08b2103be603548c3311a58ab_433041_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="487"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we were able to focus entirely on the Lenape Timetree project. We continued with significant progress on the design work. On the implementation side, we made progress on network layout adjustments, a new visual debug mode to help understand and improve the layout, and some visual cleanup. Design rolling velocity is &lt;strong>11.7&lt;/strong>; development rolling velocity is &lt;strong>5.7&lt;/strong> but only 1 point and 3 development issues were closed, in part due to partial team stafing during the iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/27/featured-lenape-timetree-visual-debug.png"
alt="Screenshot showing Lenape Timetree with visual debug mode turned on"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing Lenape Timetree with visual debug mode turned on&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 27 - Mar 10, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/03/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/03/13/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/13/featured-lenape-active-leaf-style_hucd1111bb7773a1584664ae9e1e561176_810615_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="416"/>
&lt;p>In this iteration, PPA 3.9 was released, which includes a major improvement to search functionality so that similar works or reprints are clustered by default (the relevant functionality was tested and accepted the previous iteration). On the Lenape Timetree project, major design issues were accomplished for tag and leaf interactions. We also completed the first-pass implementation on the active leaf styles, hover interactions for corresponding leaf and labels, and url behavior that makes it possible to bookmark the tree with a specific leaf showing. We also contributed to some small bugfixes and a major indexing speed improvement for the Geniza project — work that was previously left in-progress, and benefited from a recent discovery made while working on PPA that made it possible to optimize the database queries used for bulk indexing (indexing all Geniza documents went from somewhere around 20-30 minutes to ~2 minutes.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity is stable, at &lt;strong>7 points&lt;/strong>, but this is due to the large number of points closed in the previous iteration when we completed the PPA search clustering functionality. We only completed &lt;strong>4 points&lt;/strong> of development work in the current iteration. The design velocity is on an upward trend, with two very productive iterations in a row, reflecting the substantial amount of design progress on the Lenape Timetree project in recent weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/13/featured-lenape-active-leaf-style.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree showing active leaf style"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree showing active leaf style&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 13 - Feb 24, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/02/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/27/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/featured-ppa-cluster-on-browse_hu2b2e8c7ec08532430d7ad39a42c4c6fa_252621_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="361"/>
&lt;p>At long last, we finally completed the PPA issues for clustering search results by default, after multiple rounds of testing, and addressing a few regressions introduced by the changes.
A new version of parasolr (0.9) has been released with the needed grouping functionality,
and we expect to release a new version of PPA with the functionality early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the Lenape Timetree project, we&amp;rsquo;ve made tremendous progress on design work for leaves in various states and other interactions, and saw some progress on improving the layout of the tree (multiline labels, adjusted leaf sizes, adjusted sizing for century bands.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the large PPA work that was finally completed, we closed &lt;strong>12&lt;/strong> development points for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>6.67&lt;/strong> — up significantly from preceding iterations, but probably higher than we expect going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/featured-ppa-cluster-on-browse.png"
alt="Screenshot of PPA archive search/browse showing clustered results."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of PPA archive search/browse showing clustered results.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/lenape-timetree-multiline-labels.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project, which now has multiline labels and adjusted leaf sizes."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project, which now has multiline labels and adjusted leaf sizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 30 - Feb 10, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/02/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/13/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/13/featured-lenape-leaves_hub5256ca78b523dea52a63b5d1b97f5f3_449673_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="504"/>
&lt;p>The only project with issues closed this iteration is the Lenape Princeton Timetree. We made progress on a number of design issues, and completed features to represent the data points as leaves and embed images in leaf details. There was some progress on
PPA to address issues found in testing, but the work was stalled with problems updating the staging site to deliver for retesting. Our rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>3.67&lt;/strong> and holding pretty steady for now around three points.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/13/featured-lenape-leaves.png"
alt="Screenshot of current development version of the Lenape Princeton Timetree, showing leaf shapes and latest leaf data"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of current development version of the Lenape Princeton Timetree, showing leaf shapes and latest leaf data&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 16 - Jan 27, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/01/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/30/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/30/featured-lenape-colors-typography_hu265ad66af4bec21e1d4dad9d3a715521_381768_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="398"/>
&lt;p>This iteration, we completed a lot of design and development work on Lenape. We also made progress on PPA, but there is a complicated group of related features that needs a few small changes after the most recent round of testing; we hope to complete those and deliver them to production in the coming iteration. The low development velocity (&lt;strong>3 points&lt;/strong>) is consistent over the last few weeks, but significantly impacted by the amount of team member time spent on teaching for Wintersession and H+DSI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/30/featured-lenape-colors-typography.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site, with colors and typography implemented"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site, with colors and typography implemented&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 9 — Jan 13, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/01/17-january/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:01:02 +0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/17-january/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-january/featured-lenape-tree-labels_hu47de2d5b648f831843d3269aaebd6eb3_376536_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="416"/>
&lt;p>Tracking early January as a short iteration for reporting purposes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made some progress on PPA and Lenape Timetree; we also completed some chores related to Ansible, including the replication playbook that has been in use in draft status for months and a task to update vault passwords due to the recent LastPass breach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also have work nearly complete enabling contractor deploy for Princeton Geniza Project. The issue is not tracked here because the pull request is still under review, but the new setup was used successfully for version 4.12 of Geniza listed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-january/featured-lenape-tree-labels.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site with preliminary labels attached to leaves"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site with preliminary labels attached to leaves&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 12 — 23, 2022</title><link>/blog/2023/01/17-december/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:01:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/17-december/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-december/featured-lenape-select-leaf_hu5c167c8ca3f1eb09a0f1148309fd88b3_239070_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="417"/>
&lt;p>We fixed a couple of bugs on Princeton Geniza Project and tagged deployed a micro release to get the fixes into production. We also made some progress on the Lenape Timetree project. It isn&amp;rsquo;t reflected in the closed issues listed below, but we did make significant progress on PPA development work; we simply were not able to deliver for testing or close the issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-december/featured-lenape-select-leaf.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree preliminary development site (largely unstyled) showing details for a single selected leaf."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree preliminary development site (largely unstyled) showing details for a single selected leaf.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>