<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dev/Design @ CDH – Iteration Reports</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/</link><description>Recent content in Iteration Reports on Dev/Design @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/blog/iteration-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: June 7, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/06/june-7-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/06/june-7-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/06/june-7-2021/featured_geniza_prelim_search_hua1ec862dfc1584070957db372a1cd828_91060_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="508"/>
&lt;p>Our focus this iteration was on Geniza work as we finished out the second phase of work and created our first production release: we successfully migrated the Princeton Geniza Project metadata from a Google Sheets spreadsheet into the new relational database!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work leading up to the 0.3 release included further refinements to the editor/translator data import, various CSV exports for content editors and a feed to keep the current public PGP site up to date with changes made in the database. After the release, we did some follow up work to make some adjustments to the admin interface, address a couple of bugs found after the code went to production, and a very preliminary version of the public document search. Those updates have not yet been deployed, and another set of updates are still in progress or awaiting testing, so some wrap-up work will continue into the next iteration. As part of wrapping up this phase of work, we closed a number of experimental tasks on GitHub that are no longer relevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story points trend for the last two iterations (18 points each, rolling velocity of 15) shows the kind of momentum that is possible at this phase of a project, but also reflects the staffing adjustments we made to ensure we met our deadline to finish the metadata migration before the end of May.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured_geniza_prelim_search.png"
alt="Screenshot of the preliminary version of the Geniza public search"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the preliminary version of the Geniza public search&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 24, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/05/may-24-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/05/may-24-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/05/may-24-2021/featured-ppa-focus-styles_hu6c4290d7aabc7625ef86de2acc93b221_73095_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="291"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed 18 development points on Geniza as we work towards a first release and migrating the metadata from the spreadsheet to the new relational database. We also completed a smattering of bugfixes and chores as part of planned maintenance work, and one unplanned bugfix. The 18 point total brings our rolling velocity up to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notable development work completed this iteration are related to scholarship record data import and editing functionality, as well as handling demerge on import and improving the admin document search. For design, we made progress on content pages, updates to the auto-layout in Figma, and progress on typefaces, even though no design issues were closed this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-prosody-archive">Princeton Prosody Archive&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Planned maintenance work on PPA included an update to switch out the frontend library Semantic UI, which is no longer being maintained, for the community fork, Fomantic UI. The other notable change is an improvement to hover and focus styles, for better accessibility and consistency.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released minor update with a trivial bugfix to address something we missed in the 3.0 release, so that content editors can customize the preview text displayed for blog posts. We also closed a few more bug issues that are no longer relevant now that we&amp;rsquo;ve switched from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-footnote-transcription.png"
alt="Screenshot of Geniza admin interface for a scholarship record footnote with transcription"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Geniza admin interface for a scholarship record footnote with transcription&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-ppa-focus-styles.png"
alt="Screenshot of PPA archive search showing new focus styles for improved accessibility"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of PPA archive search showing new focus styles for improved accessibility&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 10, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/05/may-10-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/05/may-10-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/05/may-10-2021/featured-geniza-document-detail_hu2f9aee1d5d69e0ebe1a73f8355b78149_2751041_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="441"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed 10 development points for a rolling velocity of 8. Our primary focus was on Princeton Geniza Project, but we did a small amount of planned work on the CDH website, ansible deploy scripts, and a very small amount of unplanned work on Shakespeare and Company Project to fix a time-sensitive bug.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Accepted development work consists of a preliminary document detail page for the public site and admin editing enhancements, including a footnote count for the source list in admin, a way to edit and link to documents on the fragment edit view, and a certainty flag for TextBlocks to handle potential joins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Completed design work includes a decision on document titles for detail pages as well as search and browse, revisions to the document detail page based on the initial implementation, and completed wireframes for sort and filter on search for all screens.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed planned maintenance and released version 3.0.2 — this update removes all mezzanine dependencies and resets database migrations, making it possible for the site to finally be upgraded to newer versions of django and wagtail. This also resolved a bug in the 3.0 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The bugfix release was a small change to address a limitation on the 100 years twitter code — it did not handle subscriptions and renewals with no known duration, as revealed by a tweet on Monday. The bugfix was out in time to handle the next occurrence on Friday.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-document-detail.png"
alt="Screenshot of preliminary document detail page for Princeton Geniza Project"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of preliminary document detail page for Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: April 26, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/04/april-26-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/04/april-26-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/04/april-26-2021/featured-pgp-change-history_hu9f9e5ad30b3f4175f68327304d5cb344_33364_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="123"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed 11 development points for a rolling velocity of 19, still coming down from the massive number of points closed three iterations ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made more improvements to the data import, fixing Language+Script mapping based on the new display names and resolving all previously unhandled languages, and most notably parsing history input information (names and dates) into structured django log entries to preserve the known edit history of PGP documents. We also completed preliminary work on footnote models for linking scholarship records to documents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For design, wireframes for cluster view browse and search results pages for all screens (desktop, tablet, mobile) were all completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We fixed a couple more bugs in the 3.0 version and released a planned 3.0.1 cleanup release to remove exodus code specific to the shift to wagtail. This is a necessary step to removing mezzanine, which will finally let us upgrade to newer versions of Dljango and python.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-pgp-change-history.png"
alt="Screenshot of change history for a test imported document showing historic changes"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of change history for a test imported document showing historic changes&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="pgp-first-last-edits.png"
alt="Screenshot of earliest and most recent changes for a test import document, shown on the document dit form"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of earliest and most recent changes for a test import document, shown on the document dit form&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: April 12, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/04/april-12-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/04/april-12-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/04/april-12-2021/featured-sco_map_essay_hu5a7f23e9c9277fbc92bf6da0a0ea5ae8_1305134_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="331"/>
&lt;p>The development points for this iteration were quite low (only 4 points), but our rolling velocity continues to be unnusually high (26 points) based on the last two iterations, which were included an enormous amount of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on the design velocidy graph, we might be finding a new rhythm with design work on our new adjusted design schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finally finished and deployed the 3.0 release, migrating content from the outdated and unsupported Mezzanine to Wagtail. This iteration included a few issues to close out the release, deploying the update and running the exodus script to convert content, and then some bugfixes and clean up work for a planned 3.0.1 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we finished some smaller work related to the database and admin sorting, and made progress on document detail designs. Multiple larger features were delivered late in the iteration, which didn&amp;rsquo;t give enough time for testing to be completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low points this iteration may in part be a result of successful acceptance testing last iteration, which meant we had no in-progress work at the start of the iteration, as we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past. Rolling velocity will smooth out the volatility here, as intended.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company">Shakespeare and Company&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We had a small release for S&amp;amp;co with one bug fix (tested last iteration) and an enhancement adapted from PPA, to support embedding dynamic content (such as the map below) in Analysis essays and other site content pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-sco_map_essay.png"
alt="Screenshot of the dynamic map embedded in the newly published essay on the Literary Right Bank on Shakespeare and Company Project"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the dynamic map embedded in the newly published essay on the &lt;a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/analysis/2021/04/literary-right-bank/">Literary Right Bank&lt;/a> on Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: March 29, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/march-29-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/march-29-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/march-29-2021/featured-cdhweb-page-history_hu3ccb080dc3feaf0cdac3a01620139301_83318_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="359"/>
&lt;p>The points and total number of issues closed for the last iteration is quite high — 42 points total, 25 for cdhweb and 17 for geniza, which results in a rolling velocity of 27. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think this is a sign that we&amp;rsquo;re gaining momentum on geniza work, but suspect that the high numbers are due to work that rolled over from the last iteration and a significant push to finish cdhweb 3.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on building out the database and importing existing data. New features include a document suppression feature, automatic tracking of historic shelfmarks, and a &amp;ldquo;needs review&amp;rdquo; field where content editors can add notes about problems or questions in the data that are used to create a queue of records with problems to be addressed. We also finished testing on data import issues from previous iterations, most notably preliminary document &amp;amp; fragment import.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed features related to blog migration and managing site menus and navigation via wagtail, and resolved a number of longstanding bugs that are no longer an issue now that the site is on wagtail instead of mezzanine. There are only a few small issues rolling over for final testing and review before the 3.0 release can be created and deployed production.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-awaiting-review.png"
alt="Screenshot of Geniza admin interface with new awaiting review feature"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Geniza admin interface with new awaiting review feature&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="cdhweb-wagtail-recents.png"
alt="Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing recent edits, based on page history events"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing recent edits, based on page history events&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-cdhweb-page-history.png"
alt="Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing page history with migration event"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing page history with migration event&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: March 15, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/march-15-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/march-15-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/march-15-2021/featured-geniza-tagnetwork-detail_hu92be73fe69a8d7f2888c82f5551e2265_5116992_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="400"/>
&lt;p>Rolling velocity for this iteration increased from about 10 points to about 15 points, largely due to a substantial chunk of CDH website user stories that completed the testing process together after multiple iterations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed testing on a large set of issues that have been rolling over through multiple iterations, including major changes to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Events&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People &amp;amp; Profiles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project, Grants, and Grant Memberships&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Work is still in progress on content management updates for Blog Posts, the last major module to migrate as part of the v3.0 update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed the admin management interface for Documents, the primary model in the Geniza database. In addition, we added new functionality to track where and how often languages &amp;amp; scripts are used by Documents, including provision for probable or uncertain language identification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To support upcoming functionality for de-merging composite documents, we added an option to &amp;ldquo;clone&amp;rdquo; Documents with a record of the process stored in the database. We also experimented with clustering tags assigned to documents in order to start finding patterns in the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the design side, we completed revisions to the sitemap diagram and created a low-fidelity mockup of the public view for Documents to spark discussion on content structure and hierarchy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four user stories related to the interface and data import process for Fragments are still in-progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-tagnetwork-detail.png"
alt="Visualization of tag network generated from Geniza document tags"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Visualization of tag network generated from Geniza document tags&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-document-admin.png"
alt="Screenshot of administrative interface for Geniza document database"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of administrative interface for Geniza document database&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: March 1, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/march-1-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/march-1-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/march-1-2021/featured-geniza-language-admin_huddcbf6b09e7aaa0ac1befe273c5630ef_107246_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="479"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we continued to make progress on building out the new relational database for the Geniza project and importing existing data from spreadsheets. Database structure, admin interface, and data import for languages &amp;amp; scripts are complete; data import for library collections are complete but the admin editing story is not yet complete due to changes in the requirements. Database structure, and admin interface for documents and fragments are underway and far enough along to share a list of questions and necessary data work for the import to proceed, but have not yet been delivered for testing. In terms of design work, issues were delivered with proposed sitemap for sign off and mockups for the structure and content of the document detail page, but neither were closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Progress on the CDH website migration continues, and while some testing took place this iteration no stories were accepted and completed. There are now eight issues (24 story points) awaiting testing, up from the seven issues (18 points) reported at the beginning of the end of the last iteration. This could be due to a new acceptance tester learning the process combined with complicated issues, but it raises concerns, especially since some issues have already been tested more than once and are not yet accepted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-language-admin.png"
alt="Screenshot of Django admin interface for Languages and Scripts in the test Geniza database"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Django admin interface for Languages and Scripts in the test Geniza database&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: February 15, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/02/february-15-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/february-15-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed a significant number of issues for the Geniza project; the completed development work was all related to prototypes from the first phase (IIIF images with transcription, experimenting with eScriptorium, and two stories for a multilingual prototype). We also closed two design issues related to the sitemap &amp;amp; site flow diagram and the holistic search. We started implementing the new Geniza database and admin site, but have not yet delivered any issues for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on the CDH web development, but testing was blocked since we lost our previous acceptance tester. Seven issues (18 story points) are in &amp;ldquo;development complete&amp;rdquo; status, and a new tester has been identified and will be trained this iteration, so hope to see significant progress there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rolling development velocity of &lt;strong>8.7&lt;/strong> is plausible, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say how accurate that will be as we move from prototyping into database development and data import scripts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: February 1, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/02/february-1-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/february-1-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/02/february-1-2021/featured-geniza-sitemap_hu460cea3d9fdce17d8ee1dbdbd941b1b8_1071960_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="207"/>
&lt;p>Last iteration we made substantial progress on the cdhweb &amp;ldquo;exodus&amp;rdquo; from mezzanine to wagtail: features related to editing and &amp;ldquo;exodizing&amp;rdquo; content pages and uploaded images have been tested and accepted, and more work is underway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active development was paused on Geniza, but design work continued on a revised sitemap / site flow diagram for the new PGP site and reports to share information from usability testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Development work on Shakespeare and Company Project was to support updated data exports; version 1.1 of the datasets were published January 29th. The parasolr hotfix was due to a problem identified in prepping the Shakespeare and Company Project release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also deployed version 3.5 of PPA to production at the beginning of this iteration (the release updates and prep were completed before the holidays), which enabled the team to finally add new content from HathiTrust. (Read a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ProsodyArchive/status/1349391218296434692">twitter thread of new works added&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-sitemap.png"
alt="Sitemap/site flow diagram for new Princeton Geniza Project site (view on Figma)"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Sitemap/site flow diagram for new Princeton Geniza Project site (&lt;a href="https://www.figma.com/file/HpGBOZi9lO8B3nCAx3d4Fj/Princeton-Geniza?node-id=415%3A2">view on Figma&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Version 1.1 of &lt;a href="https://dataspace.princeton.edu/handle/88435/dsp01fx719q532">Shakespeare and Company Project Datasets&lt;/a>, including updated readmes and change logs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: January 11, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/01/january-11-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/01/january-11-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Due to the holidays and planned vacations, we decided to take a long iteration spanning from December 14th to the end of the first week in January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We spent the majority of the time on maintenance and addressing some technical debt. The CDH website was successfully moved from Research Computing and a MySQL database to its new home on a PUL VM and running on the PUL Postgresql database server. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on CDH web 3.0, which involves the transition (which we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to call &amp;ldquo;exodus&amp;rdquo; to avoid confusion with &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo;) from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration we also finally successfully addressed the problem in PPA for adding new HathiTrust content. The release was tagged December 22nd, along with a supporting release of parasolr, but rather than deploy an update right before the holidays, it was held. That release will go into production early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu">CDH website&lt;/a> v2.8.1 update was largely an infrastructural one, so there is little that is visible to display and we expect and want it to look it exactly as before.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One visible change: emoji are now supported! See &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/updates/2020/11/18/dating-problems-ask-princeton-geniza-project-team/">Marina&amp;rsquo;s post on dates and dating&lt;/a> to see the emojis she originally included, which were not supported on the previous version of the site.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: December 14, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/12/december-14-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/12/december-14-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we paused active software development on the Geniza project, although design research and work on sitemap and continued, along with planning for the next phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We shifted development efforts to an infrastructure migration for the CDH website and planning for CDH web 3.0, which consists of a major migration to move content management functionality from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was also development effort on Shakespeare and Company Project with the main goal of generating updated dataset exports in January, although we did address a handful of small bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration we also had PPA work become unblocked: the revised solution for adding new content from HathiTrust was blocked by errors with rsync, which were finally resolved this iteration, so the feature was finally delivered for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because the work this iteration was largely focused on infrastructure and data, there is nothing visual to demo. The high number of development issues closed relative to points reflects the number of bugs and chores closed, and also reflects the fact that much of the work for CDH web remains in-progress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 30, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/featured-geniza-tags_hue9cb7085157941caad4966623a815cc8_192671_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="120"/>
&lt;p>This was our last scheduled iteration for working on Geniza prototyping,
so we made a push to finish as much of that work as possible before we switch to other things. Work completed includes a report of name extracted from metadata descriptions, to help with data work and future data migrations; an experimental tag filter that allows the user to select how tags are combined; and a keyword search on the experimental holistic search (the latter two will be used for usability testing). We also delivered for testing a simplistic implementation of TEI transcriptions converted to IIIF annotations and displayed in the Mirador 3 viewer, and finished work on a django prototype with internationalization. Unfortunately, complications with the deploy of the second prorotype meant we were unable to deliver that work for testing last week before the Thanksgiving holiday. No design tasks were marked as completed on GitHub, and the design work at this phase is still largely UX research; but there are in-progress design tasks for document detail page, holistic search results, and preliminary sitemap that we expect to close in this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration also includes 5 points from a CDH web feature that was completed in the previous iteration, and a CDH web release with updates completed in the last iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-tags.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-cluster-search.png"
alt="Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 16, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/featured-cluster-prototype_huc4dfd2b8c37a1e52c03ddc05f78843df_330385_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="479"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made substantial progress on our Geniza search prototyping, most notably implementing the first two steps towards a prototype of the holistic search interface that Gissoo has been designing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some updates and fixed some bugs for CDH web, towards a maintenance release that will go out early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-cluster-prototype.png"
alt="Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 2, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/featured-startwords-weaving-interface_hu6f24b4b9c5af428670450e95cc68919c_571393_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="335"/>
&lt;p>Very pleased to report that this past iteration we finally published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/">Issue One of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. The velocity charts below reflect the effort to get this out the door, including completion of design and implementation on an experimental piece and a large amount of work to finish converting the long &amp;ldquo;Data Beyond Vision&amp;rdquo; essay and related snippets to markdown, and to finish custom styles for the essay, including PDF styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also continuing our work on prototyping and data exploration for the Geniza project; this iteration saw our first two search prototype stories accepted. We also published the charter for the Geniza research partnership; it&amp;rsquo;s available at &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re also continuing to make progress switching our GitHub repositories to a default branch of &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong>. In the last iteration, we updated the Ansible deploys to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> by default for production deploys, and updated all projects with a production deploy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-startwords-weaving-interface.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Startwords experimental Weaving as Interface piece"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> experimental &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/weaving-as-interface/">Weaving as Interface&lt;/a> piece&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="startwords-dbv-pdf.png"
alt="Screenshot from the Startwords PDF for Data Beyond Vision"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot from the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> PDF for &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: October 19th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/featured-dbv-visuals_hu5a4dd102ce4f0bcbe542030242904bd8_198769_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="207"/>
&lt;p>Last iteration we put a lot of time and effort into Startwords as we get close to our issue 1 deadline and launch date, although that&amp;rsquo;s not reflected in the number of tickets closed on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on Geniza planning and prototyping. That isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly evident from the issues closed, but that&amp;rsquo;s in part because we were hung up on getting the hostname for the new test server and acceptance testing only started at the end of the iteration. Design work at this point is primarily research, which we have not been tracking on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some minor improvements to our ansible deploys and dev/design site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-dbv-visuals.png"
alt="Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="dbv-icons.png"
alt="Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-search-prototype.png"
alt="Geniza search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: October 5th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/october-5th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/october-5th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration marked our official start of work on the Geniza research partnership, now that the charter has been signed. We made progress on data modeling and a preliminary search prototype, but since none of those tasks have been completed they aren&amp;rsquo;t reflected in the issues and points below. We also saw a lot of activity on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, as the team makes the push to complete remaining functionality and styles needed for the project launch. We also made progress on PPA maintenance and bug fixes, although the fixes have not yet been released to production, and one bug fix is ready for testing but blocked waiting on HathiTrust restoring rsync dataset access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> article image styles — see on &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision draft article&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/notfound">404 page designs&lt;/a> have been implemented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://parasolr.readthedocs.io/en/develop/gettingstarted.html">Basic &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; documentation for parasolr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: September 21st, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/september-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/september-21st-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration included work to complete cdh-web version 2.7, which consisted of maintenance upgrades and a few helpful features for fall; maintenance and bug fixes on PPA, including a refactor to use in-house Solr library parasolr, removing a dependency on a forked, unmaintained SolrClient; and continued progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major work not reflected here includes the final revisions on charter for the CDH/Geniza research partnership, which was signed and approved today, and improved planning and documentation for the steps to close out a project when a research partnership grant ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CDH web &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/people/affiliates/">affiliates page now includes staff, such as PUL librarians directing data curation projects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CDH web events can now be designated as virtual, and take an optional URL for joining the virtual event&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: September 8th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/featured_startwords_404design_huff12e89c7eb4ae2479e06a3c7a794ddf_79450_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="379"/>
&lt;p>The last iteration we continued to spend time on project maintenance and updates. Closed issues on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> and the pucas release are continuing and closing out work from the previous iterations. Active work this iteration that is incomplete and not reflected in the closed tickets include django/mezzanine upgrades for cdhweb, and refactoring PPA to remove an outdated SolrClient dependency and use parasolr instead. We also have now migrated our first repositories to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> as the production branch name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last iteration we also wrote a new &lt;em>limited support agreement&lt;/em>, which was adapted and simplified from the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3359203">&amp;ldquo;Built by CDH&amp;rdquo; Long Term Service Agreement&lt;/a> in order to offer minimal support for the &lt;a href="https://pemm.cdh.princeton.edu/">PEMM Incipit Search Tool&lt;/a> for a limited term (1 year, renewable for a second year). The limited support agreement for PEMM goes into effect today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/">New dev/design site&lt;/a> (still in progress)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.figma.com/file/MEt3gfKX4N3WTLPbLGBbGC/Startwords?node-id=1104%3A3516">404 error design&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Articles now have image styles with automatic derivatives for different size screens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured_startwords_404design.png"
alt="Screenshot of new 404 page design for Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of new 404 page design for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: August 24th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/august-24th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/august-24th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Not a lot of development work reported on GitHub because the primary team focus continues to be planning the new Research Partnership project. This iteration also included time spent on two internal project retrospectives (Shakespeare and Company Project, PEMM) and a CDH Retreat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active development work included progress on PPA bugfixes (delivered for testing but not complete) and minor maintenance updates to django-pucas (removing support for python 2.7 to fix the a failing master build, in preparation for migrating from master to main).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The long list of &amp;ldquo;wontfix&amp;rdquo; issues in the mep-django is a result of cleaning up GitHub for Shakespeare and Company Project to close issues that were postponed or wishlisted on the way to a 1.0 release and we no longer plan to work on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: August 10th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/august-10th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/august-10th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Three week iteration due to multiple team member week-long vacations. Less development work than usual because the primary team focus has been on planning the new Research Partnership project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: July 21st, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/07/july-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/07/july-21st-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>PEMM release with final updates to close out grant year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shakespeare and Company Project updates related to publishing 1.0 data exports; includes 100 years twitter bot code&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: June 30th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/06/june-30th-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/june-30th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Lots of progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, but no official release until Issue 1 is ready.
PEMM release put off until this iteration since only one feature was completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demo">Demo&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="_startwords_">&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Scrollable contextual notes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/about/">We have an about page!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/the-body-as-data/">Pull quote!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/stack-shakespeare-and-company-membership-activities/">Our first short piece!!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/#-">Amazing pit bar&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Princeton-CDH/startwords/issues/22#issuecomment-651201652">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>