<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dev/Design @ CDH – Iteration Reports</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/</link><description>Recent content in Iteration Reports on Dev/Design @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/blog/iteration-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Jul 25 - Aug 5, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/08/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/08/15/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/15/featured-sw3-home-es_hu69c047a2f4fcedf58044d2b58d1f46ce_322226_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="424"/>
&lt;p>Belated iteration report, due to vacations last week. We closed a lot of development work (16 points, 23 issues); this is likely due to the transcription editor functionality that was tested and accepted and the number of small chores in the final push to get Startwords issue 3 out the door.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finally published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/3/">Startwords issue 3&lt;/a>! GitHub issues completed in this iteration were chores related to getting the release out and quick bug fixes to address problems we discovered after the issue was published.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Version 4.6 went into production, with the new image + transcription viewer. We also tested closed a number of features related to the transcription editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We started ramping back up on PPA development work this iteration, beginning with some python package updates and a few small chores.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-sw3-home-es.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords home page in Spanish with Issue 3 published"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords home page in Spanish with Issue 3 published&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 4 - Jul 22, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/07/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/25/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/07/25/featured_geniza_itt_huc4dd34ec8528b5941c858b1d744782a9_3118254_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="313"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed implementation of the MVP for the new image + transcription viewing panel on the document details page on the Princeton Geniza Project site. Specific features completed include image zoom controls (zoom is no longer enabled by default, which resolves some accessibility problems and avoids making the zoom a scroll trap) and switching between editions when a document has more than one transcription. We also completed work on a revised tag style, a change which was needed to properly handle accessibility checks and making sure that tags are always big enough tap targets. Although we completed the MVP functionality for the new viewer, we were delayed with releasing it to the production site due to a change in the interim transcription format and problems synchronizing transcriptions for documents with more than one edition, which requires data work to resolve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We completed 7 points of development work (10 issues) for a rolling velocity of 9.3; design work was impacted by staff unavailability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured_geniza_itt.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new image and transcription panel interface from the Princeton Geniza Project, showing image zoom controls."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new image and transcription panel interface from the Princeton Geniza Project, showing image zoom controls.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza_new_tag.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results with revised tag styles."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results with revised tag styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jun 7 - Jun 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/06/21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/21/featured_geniza_datesortfilter_hu37daa875e16c4aed843a1ec6b98ccb96_93893_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="751"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our primary focus was on Princeton Geniza Project, but we did close a few more issues related to the upcoming Startwords issue 3. Our development velocity is on an upward trend — we closed &lt;strong>21&lt;/strong> development points (16 issues), which gives us a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>13.7&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we released version 4.5, which adds several features related to document date functionality: calendar conversion in admin for simple cases with Anno Mundi and Hijri calendars, improved date display on document details, and sorting and filtering search results by date. We also rolled out the new &amp;ldquo;related documents&amp;rdquo; page, improved image credits display for JTS content, and fixed a bug with handling Heidelberg IIIF. This update required a supporting release of &lt;code>djiffy&lt;/code>, to add support for displaying Creative Commons licenses in addition to rightstatements.org licenses. Several features for the new image+transcription panel viewer were tested but not released; they won&amp;rsquo;t go out until we have a full replacement for the current display, hopefully in the next release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finished work on the new authors list page, adjusted the footer to add a link to the authors page, and completed a few other small style-related changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured_geniza_datesortfilter.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search page with document date filter and sort options."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search page with document date filter and sort options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="startwords-authors.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords author list page."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords author list page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 23 - Jun 3, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/06/06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/06/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/06/featured_startwords-textshadows_hueb450c0ae95931c0a7535cfca2ce0352_362871_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="544"/>
&lt;p>We adjusted the schedule to make the past iteration a three-week iteration due to the Memorial holiday resulting in a very short week. Due to holidays, team member availability, and the chunks of work that are in progress, we didn&amp;rsquo;t publish any releases, but we did complete a lot of work. Our development velocity is up to &lt;strong>9.3&lt;/strong> points (14 points, 21 issues). We have the same exact velocity for design work (&lt;strong>9.3&lt;/strong>), with 12 points and 7 issues closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Major design work closed related to the new image and transcription panel, for which implementation are underway. We also completed designs for the related documents page. We also finished work on a number of features related to date filtering and historical calendar conversion, which we hope to make available in production soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed much of the remaining work needed for issue 3, including: revised shadow text styles for the site homepage and single issue pages (pictured below), generalized the interlude styles invented for SW issue 1 so it can be used in any article in future; improved DOI display for translated articles; and fixed a couple of bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-ansible">cdh-ansible&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A small improvement in our project deploy scripts, suggested by PUL staff, resulted in a huge improvement in the time it takes to deploy projects, by configuring the deploy scripts to skip one-time setup tasks by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured_startwords-textshadows.png"
alt="Screenshot of the development version of Startwords showing the newly redesigned and reimplemented text shadows and three-feature essay layout."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the development version of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> showing the newly redesigned and reimplemented text shadows and three-feature essay layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 2 - May 13, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/05/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/16/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We released Geniza v4.4 early in this iteration to deliver work completed in the previous iteration, and then quickly discovered and fixed a bug with the menu button that made the site unnavigable on mobile. We did not get another release out during the iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made progress on a number of design and development issues and both rolling velocity and iteration development work are at &lt;strong>6 points&lt;/strong>. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect the large amount of in-progress work on transcription functionality (delivered for first-round testing but still very much in progress) and several related features around date/calendar conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No development work this iteration, but design work for issue 3 is nearly complete and editorial and design work will be ready soon for final handoff for development on the remaining items needed for completing this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 18 - Apr 29, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/05/02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/02/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/05/02/featured-geniza-doc-details_hu6e508823ce402b666b0a6fbd9a76aa08_128232_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="528"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made progress on Geniza and closed out several issues for Startwords. We weren&amp;rsquo;t able to get a release out with the Geniza updates due to team commitments and availability at the end of the iteration, but we hope to get a release out early this iteration with the completed work. Our development velocity is fairly steady at &lt;strong>5&lt;/strong> points, but we closed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> development points and &lt;strong>17&lt;/strong> issues. We&amp;rsquo;re also continuing to make good progress with design work on both projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notable work includes improvements to the public search — a filter for documents with images, options to sort by input date and shelfmark, and our first foray into Judaeo-Arabic conversion, making it possible to search on Judaeo-Arabic transcription content when inputting Arabic search terms. We updated the admin document view so that it uses the same image and transcription viewer as the public site, and improved the display and functionality in the IIIF image rights in that section. We also made progress on RTL design implementations, resolved a long-standing font loading issue in Percy, and finally set up Sphinx code documentation. We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on design and development for the new transcription functionality, although we have not yet been able to deliver it for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finalized designs for the new author list and linking to the author page in the footer, and completed testing on issues for reading articles and issues in translation and toggling between languages. We delivered a draft version of Issue 3 to the contributors with their revisions, so we are getting closer to publishing this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-doc-details.png"
alt="Screenshot of revised document details page"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of revised document details page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-sort-options.png"
alt="Screenshot of document search with new sorts and filters"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of document search with new sorts and filters&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-image-rights.png"
alt="Screenshot of revised image rights and permalink on document details page"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of revised image rights and permalink on document details page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 5 - Apr 16, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/04/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/18/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/18/featured-startwords-multilingual_hu323df8a84995277b79811538ff69610f_256815_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="382"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made progress on the remaining multilingual functionality and other features needed to publish &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> issue 3. We didn&amp;rsquo;t close a lot of points on the Geniza project because the major work going on at this point is prototyping and beginning to implement the new transcription functionality, and sketching out design ideas for the public display and interaction of images with transcription and translation content. Our rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>4.67&lt;/strong>, due to the low number of points completed in the last two iterations (3, 4). We expect this to pick up once we move out of the transcription prototyping phase and finish work on the Startwords issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-startwords-multilingual.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords development site with multilingual functionality: translated navigation and paratext, available language indicators"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords development site with multilingual functionality: translated navigation and paratext, available language indicators&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 21 - Apr 1, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/04/04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/04/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/04/featured-startwords-issue-langs_hu4c7ef2aa063be4f046914b1e883493b9_94528_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="347"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we worked on needed functionality for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> Issue 3, and made more progress prototyping and testing functionality for a transcription solution for the Geniza project. Because much of the development work consisted of chores, exploratory or prototyping, our iteration velocity and rolling velocity are both fairly low. We did make significant progress with Design work, both for Geniza and Startwords.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-startwords-issue-langs.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords issue list, which now includes indicators for available languages."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> issue list, which now includes indicators for available languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Published new &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> documentation pages: &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/guides/editorial-guidelines/">Editorial Guidelines&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/guides/style-guide/">Contributor Style Guide&lt;/a> (both linked from the About page)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://pgp-transcription-prototype.glitch.me/">Geniza transcription experiments and prototypes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 7 - Mar 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/03/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/21/featured-document-detail_hu887688024267b446f1b1936aa274aecc_84252_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="777"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our focus again was solely on the Geniza project. We put out a bug-fix release early in the iteration to address several highly noticeable problems that were identified by various members of the team, and then a feature release with new functionality, most notably implementing Turbo and Stimulus to make the document search more responsive and load changes more quickly. We also made some small changes to the document details page, including displaying primary and secondary languages, linking to other documents on the same fragments, and moving secondary metadata lower on the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our development rolling velocity is steady at &lt;strong>13 points&lt;/strong>, although this iteration we only closed &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong> story points. However, that&amp;rsquo;s in line with what we should expect, since it was effectively a half iteration in terms of developer staffing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-document-detail.png"
alt="Updates to document details page, including language, links to other documents on the same fragments, and secondary metadata made less prominent."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Updates to document details page, including language, links to other documents on the same fragments, and secondary metadata made less prominent.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 21 - Mar 4, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/03/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/07/featured-geniza-filters_hu56b64b3cea7385267f391b2335cd3a21_670917_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="347"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we were primarily focused on Geniza, but did devote some efforts towards Startwords. Our development velocity has stabilized a bit: 13 points, 20 issues, for a rolling velocity of 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released another update (version 4.2) with more new features and improvements to the public site. The most visible change is the filter panel on the &lt;a href="https://geniza.princeton.edu/en/documents/">document search&lt;/a>, which now includes three new filters related to scholarship records. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on designs and backend support for the RTL versions of the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we made some small progress on design and infrastructure updates needed for Issue 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-filters.png"
alt="Geniza search filters expanded on desktop, with one selected."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search filters expanded on desktop, with one selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-active-filter-icon.png"
alt="Geniza active filter icon, to indicate when search filters are applied."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza active filter icon, to indicate when search filters are applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-favicon.png"
alt="Geniza browser tab &amp;amp;amp; bookmark icon"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza browser tab &amp;amp; bookmark icon&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 7 - Feb 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/02/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/02/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/21/featured-pgp-logotype_huee92df934de27e87a094628979144288_497057_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="407"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our focus was entirely on the Princeton Geniza Project as we worked to address issues identified in the 4.0 release that we wanted to address before switching the site to the official &lt;a href="https://geniza.princeton.edu">https://geniza.princeton.edu&lt;/a> url (which we did on Thursday!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notable work completed in this iteration includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>completion of design work on the new logo and logotype (shown below), which will be integrated into the site this week.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>search results now include image thumbnails when available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>an admin document merge function, so that duplicate documents and joins can be merged manually in the admin site instead of relying on spreadsheets and script to handle merging (we discovered the script method was error-prone since merging needs to be done carefully).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Our rolling velocity for development is &lt;strong>13&lt;/strong> points; this iteration we completed 19 points (16 issues).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-pgp-logotype.png"
alt="Completed designs for new PGP logo and logotype"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Completed designs for new PGP logo and logotype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="pgp-search-images.png"
alt="Screenshot showing PGP search results with image thumbnails"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing PGP search results with image thumbnails&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 24 - Feb 4, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/02/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/02/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/07/featured-404-error_hu94ac8d84e3dc675b803d8c1cbeabc3e1_600221_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="493"/>
&lt;p>At long last, we tagged and released the 4.0 version of Princeton Geniza Project! This is meets our agreement for a &amp;ldquo;Minimum Viable Product&amp;rdquo; to replace the current PGP v3.0. The new site isn&amp;rsquo;t publicly available just yet, but we&amp;rsquo;re planning to turn off IP access restriction by Thursday of this week at the latest and hoping to switch it to the official URL within another week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We closed &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> development issues this iteration, but only completed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> story points — likely because much of our focus was on finishing implementing visual designs, fixing bugs, and finishing chores in preparation for this release. Our rolling development velocity is 20 points, due to the huge iteration in December and the fact that we&amp;rsquo;re no longer counting the zero-point iteration around Thanksgiving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mep-django releases were related to publication of the 1.2 version of the Shakespeare and Company Project datasets, which were published on Princeton&amp;rsquo;s DataSpace on January 31st.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-404-error.png"
alt="Geniza 404 Not Found error page"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza 404 Not Found error page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="500-error.png"
alt="Geniza 500 Server Error page"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza 500 Server Error page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="credits.png"
alt="Geniza credits page, showing content page styles"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza credits page, showing content page styles&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 17 - Jan 28, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/01/31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/31/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/01/31/featured-geniza-search_hu7216f1b6a544a4d2818a5a27908e21fd_224478_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="440"/>
&lt;p>Belated report on the first iteration of January 2022. This was effectively a long iteration, since it included work completed during the week of January 17th, which was a scheduled R&amp;amp;D week for CDH staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our focus continues to be exclusively on Geniza, as we work closer and closer to completing the initial MVP that will be made public. We made tremendous progress on completing design work for site visuals, implementing the designs, finishing some of the final remaining functionality, and resolving a number of small bugs and chores that needed to be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We closed 21 development issues, for a total of 11 story points and a rolling velocity of 17.3.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-search.png"
alt="Geniza search page, showing the implementation of new site visuals and colors"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search page, showing the implementation of new site visuals and colors&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 6 - Dec 31, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/01/04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/04/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We extend this iteration to four weeks, which included the Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s holidays
when most of the team was out. During this iteration, we published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/2/">the second issue of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/a> and made significant progress on the Geniza 4.0 release. We have an enormous total of &lt;strong>41&lt;/strong> development story points closed this iteration and a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>18&lt;/strong> — this is due in part to the lengthened iteration, but also due to the significant push to complete the Geniza MVP and closing out a number of large issues (three 8-point development issues and two 5s!). We also have a huge total of &lt;strong>37&lt;/strong> points (16 issues) for design work, completing the majority of the design work for the Geniza MVP. The unevenness of the design velocity likely reflects Gissoo&amp;rsquo;s observation that visual design does not fit well with an Agile development workflow, since so many things need to be designed and reviewed together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed the remaining work to publish &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/2/">Startwords Issue 2&lt;/a>; work in this iteration included miscellaneous cleanup items for final publication of the essays in issue 2, and some minor cleanup work after the publication. We also started on prep work for functionality needed for issue 3, but none of those issues were closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although we postponed the 4.0 public MVP release until January, we did make a significant amount of progress towards completing the work targeted for that MVP, and we did release a 0.7 version with a significant number of updates since the previous release. Updates include improved citation formatting for footnotes and sources, revised scholarship record view for individual documents, an import of data from the PGP v3 links database (information now included in PGP v4 scholarship records), setting up Wagtail for management of content pages, and progress with interim transcription solution for synchronization from TEI to the database, including in search results, and displaying with or without images on document detail pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made tremendous progress on design: nearly all of the design work needed for the MVP has been completed and approved, and a significant amount of work was done towards implementing site visuals implement them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New versions of djiffy and parasolr were released in support of the Geniza 0.7 release, with support for newer versions of Python &amp;amp; Django and improved functionality needed for the new Geniza search.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 22 - Dec 3, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/12/06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/12/06/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We made progress on multiple projects, but didn&amp;rsquo;t close anything with points; this is due to the Thanksgiving holiday and the shift to working on Startwords to prep issue 2 for publication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed a number of updates in preparation for publishing Startwords issue 2, which looks to be in good shape to go out on time as planned.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The issues closed largely related to design and design implementation. We do have a large issue in-progress and nearly complete to update the scholarship details for individual documents; this issue was larger than expected due to the need to format references more like a citation, which involved some data model changes. Due to the holidays and rolling work on the MVP, we have not made any releases in a while to update production with the latest changes; we probably should do this sometime soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released a micro update with maintenance updates, including python package upgrades and two minor adjustments in support of publishing new versions of the datasets. While we made the update, we added Zenode metadata and a citation file to make the GitHub repository more citable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="archiving-derridas-margins">Archiving Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This work is still not complete, but we made a small amount of progress on the final configuration needed for the archive site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 8 - Nov 19, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/11/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/11/22/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity after this iteration is picking up (7.8) as geniza work gains momentum. For development work, we completed 21 issues and 13 points. We made what we hope to be the final Derrida release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made progress on the public document search, implementing styles and typography, and a preliminary implementation for synchronizing TEI transcriptions for search and display on the new site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derrida">derrida&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We developed a custom driver for browsertrix-crawler so that we could archive the historgram visualization pages and the deep-zoom image content on the site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 25 - Nov 5, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/11/08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/11/08/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/11/08/featured-geniza-kwic_hu183aa54baf7030e3cd19aa3fb2aea662_57198_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="355"/>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity after this iteration is low (only &lt;strong>4 points&lt;/strong>), but we&amp;rsquo;re starting to gain momentum on the geniza development work and we&amp;rsquo;rec lose to wrapping up maintenance and chore work. For development work, we completed 17 issues and 9 points; we also made progress on geniza design work this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re starting to make progress on the public site features planned for the first public release (PGP v4.0): adding functionality to the public document search, document details, implementing styles, and working to use localization and internationalization consistently. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on visual design and typography.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derrida">derrida&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the work to archive Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins, we completed the remaining work to complete the web archiving (which included a custom web driver to capture the visualization and deep zoom images), and gathered needed information for customizing and configuring the deployed archive site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Startwords is not scheduled for active development until next iteration, but as we identified and addressed one small item that was determined to be helpful for editing and publication prep; in this case, so the editors could give contributors a preview of how their revised essay might be presented on the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-kwic.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Geniza search interface showing matching search terms in context in the document description"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Geniza search interface showing matching search terms in context in the document description&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 11 - Oct 22, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/10/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/10/25/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/10/25/featured-derrida-archive-banner_hue2d9c0845a5a26ef49287aa91a87af47_1434552_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="403"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed 9 development issues but had zero points, because those issues were all chores and bugs. Our rolling velocity is &lt;strong>5.67&lt;/strong> but should pick up as we gain momentum on geniza work, especially since we&amp;rsquo;ve added contractor developers to help out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a &lt;strong>cdh web&lt;/strong> bugfix release that addressed two bugs, and a &lt;strong>derrida&lt;/strong> release with the code for the final data exports. We&amp;rsquo;re ramping up on &lt;strong>geniza&lt;/strong> work for the fall, which is reflected in the number of issues closed, including some frontend setup work, planning, and progress on design for content pages and document detail page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-derrida-archive-banner.png"
alt="Screenshot of preliminary Derrida&amp;amp;rsquo;s Margins archive site with read-only banner"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of preliminary Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins archive site with read-only banner&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 27 - Oct 8, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/10/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/10/11/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/10/11/featured-geniza-darkmode_huae789e660e93d1b28032acb9e191836d_156320_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="304"/>
&lt;p>We closed a rather small number of issues this iteration (5 development issues, 3 points) bringing our rolling velocity down a bit to &lt;strong>6.33&lt;/strong>. This is likely because our efforts were directed elsewhere; notably on completing the Geniza year 2 charter, which has now been finalized and signed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made some progress closing out in-progress frontend development work on Geniza, finished the last set of updates on the Derrida data exports, and also released a bugfix for CDH web. (The bug is not listed below because it was reopened when we discovered the problem had only been partially solved.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-darkmode.png"
alt="Screenshot of the latest style updates on the Geniza document search, including setup for dark mode"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the latest style updates on the Geniza document search, including setup for dark mode&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 13 - Sep 24, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/09/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/09/27/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration, we continued working on planned maintenance work and finishing the charter for the next year of work on the Geniza research partnership. Our rolling velocity is up to &lt;strong>7.7&lt;/strong>; points for this iteration were high because work included a large feature on the Geniza project that was finally completed and several features for Derrida data exports that had been in-progress for multiple iterations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derridas-margins">Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed revisions on three of the four dataset exports, and corrected one bug in the previous version of the data exports and one bug in the IIIF image endpoint handling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finally completed the script to merge documents, and fixed a bug that made it into production when part of the incompletely tested merge code was included in the last release. We also made progress on design work towards visual identity and color selection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company">Shakespeare and Company&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We successsfully completed the migration to PUL infrastructure without hiccups, including switching the 100 years twitter bot cron job over to the new server. This update includes upgrades to python 3.6, Solr 8, and a switch from MySQL to Postgresql. Most crucially, this gets the code off of python 3.5 which has not been supported for nearly a year. Looking foward, we know have a path for testing and updating the application to newer versions of python, since the infrastructure on the PUL VMs is fully managed by our ansible deploy scripts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 23 - Sep 3, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/09/07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/09/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/09/07/featured-cdhweb-homepage_hu1bdbd80a0b6580c6bb28223084600abd_240245_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="303"/>
&lt;p>Completed points for this iteration are quite low (only &lt;strong>2 points&lt;/strong>). This brings our rolling velocity down to &lt;strong>6&lt;/strong>, which is the lowest it&amp;rsquo;s been in quite some time. This is likely due to the focus on maintenance work and chartering the next year of the Princeton Geniza Project; we also have some in-progress work on revised data exports for Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins that have not been completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-web">CDH web&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released version 3.4 with the enhancements as planned in the charter, most notably a new site search. One new feature was completed this iteration, revising the home page to call attention to important information (about CDH and consults). We also fixed a small bug impacting the staff and executive committee pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released version 0.5 with high priority fixes and improvements that had been identified by the project team to help with ongoing data work. In progress work on a script to merge documents, which has been through multiple rounds of testing, was temporarily put in the ice box to prioritize work on the Geniza charter for the next year. We did also start work more seriously on frontend development and inftrastructure and visual design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derrida">Derrida&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Maintenance work is ongoing; we successfully set up continuous integration on GitHub Actions, to aid us in testing the remaining development (since Travis-CI is no longer reliable). We made progress on the data export scripts, but none of the issues were completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made progress on maintenance work to migrate the application from the current host into PUL infrastructure, which includes a python version upgrade, new version of Solr, and switch from MySQL to Postgresql. The site is successfully running in the new QA environment, so after a bit more testing to confirm functionality and migrated data, we should be able to proceed and schedule a production migration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-cdhweb-homepage.png"
alt="Screenshot of the CDH home page showing the newly implemented design featuring the About page and Consultations"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the CDH home page showing the newly implemented design featuring the About page and Consultations&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 9 - Aug 20, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/08/23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/08/23/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/08/23/featured-cdhweb-search_hu5bdc378edbfc8df771ea880f23028bee_103240_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="360"/>
&lt;p>This iteration &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/updates/2021/08/15/rebecca-munson/">we lost Rebecca Munson&lt;/a>, who was a long-time collaborator of the CDH Development &amp;amp; Design Team, project manager &amp;amp; project coordinator for many of our projects. In spite of that terrible loss, it&amp;rsquo;s good to do work, and we did make some progress on our planned work. Among other things, we implemented a special purple mode for the CDH website and released v3.3.1 so we could turn it on to honor her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We completed &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong> development story points for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>8.67&lt;/strong>; we also completed &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> design story points, as all the design work for the CDH web v3.4 release was finalized.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-web">CDH web&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The work for the 3.4 release is nearly done, and it should be completed and go into production soon. Completed work include designs for search, better visuals to highlight the about page and consultations on the home page, and the new site search.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We started up development on Geniza again, picking up some work that was left incomplete and small changes that will be helpful to the data team. Completed work includes capability to edit historic shelfmarks for Fragments, clean up of the India Book sources that were not grouped correctly on import, and a way to view actions on the admin site beyond the most recent ten or a specific document.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-cdhweb-search.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new CDH web search"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new CDH web search&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 26 — Aug 6, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/08/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/08/9/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/08/9/featured-ppa-excerpts_hu25f15e2e6fb2a63c611d6ccbe3a67ee8_210994_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="344"/>
&lt;p>We had multiple projects active this iteration, roughly divided across developers on the team. The planned work for PPA spilled over and needed to be completed; work started on updates for CDH web identified in the recent project charter; and work continued on maintenance updates for Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins. We closed &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> issues and a total of &lt;strong>9&lt;/strong> points for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>11.3&lt;/strong>. The lower velocity reflects the kind of work we&amp;rsquo;re doing (including some maintenance), as well as other things going on, including the transition with some staff starting to work on campus again.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="project-specific-updates">Project-specific updates&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed the work on 3.7 and released the new features to production. This update includes support for Gale/ECCO content as well as excerpt support for HathiTrust materials, which is a fairly major change to the collection. We&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to a write up from the team publicizing the changes and explaining what this means for PPA.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cdhweb">CDHweb&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We released version 3.3 with support for oEmbed of Media Central videos, a new accessibility checker tool for content editors, and improved handling for moved and renamed pages. Implementation and design for the new site search is in progress, and has been successfully prototyped.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="derridas-margins">Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We made progress on maintenance updates to Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins, including a bugfix release that corrects an image display problem that has been impacting the sites for several months. Work is underway to generate revised data exports and prep the site for archiving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We completed work on two trivial changes and one data report to support data work for the next version of the data exports; the changes should go to production soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ppa-1">PPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-ppa-excerpts.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Prosody Archive search result for a book excerpt."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of &lt;em>Princeton Prosody Archive&lt;/em> search result for a book excerpt.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;h3 id="cdh-web">CDH Web&lt;/h3>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="cdhweb-editoria11y.png"
alt="Screenshot of CDH website showing the editoria11y accessibility tool which has been integrated and enabled for content editors."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of CDH website showing the &lt;a href="https://itmaybejj.github.io/editoria11y/">editoria11y accessibility tool&lt;/a> which has been integrated and enabled for content editors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="cdhweb-video-embed.png"
alt="Screenshot of CDH web admin and public view showing the video embed functionality."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of CDH web admin and public view showing the video embed functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 5 — 23, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/07/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/07/26/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/07/26/featured-percy-visualreview_hufac49881638799c2446d75f54e1a48a2_386534_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="472"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made significant progress on PPA. All remaining planned work to support Gale/ECCO import and HathiTrust excerpts were moved to &amp;ldquo;development complete&amp;rdquo; status, but unfortunately testing issues related to indexing and keyword search were problematic and held up testing on a cluster of issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a smattering of progress on other projects as well. For the CDH website, we completed work to setup a new visual testing review workflow with &lt;a href="https://percy.io/">Percy&lt;/a>, which we hope will save time and improve our design implementation testing across projects. We continued to be paused on Geniza, but we had one issue closed that should have been accepted before, but was left open based on design feedback and changes requested rather than functionality. On Startwords, we also had a very minor style bugfix resolved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We extended this iteration for 3 weeks to account for vacation and the ACH2021 conference last week. We completed 10 development points, and have a rolling development velocity of 14.3 points.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-percy-visualreview.png"
alt="Screenshot from Percy showing an example of visual review for a page on CDH web"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot from Percy showing an example of visual review for a page on CDH web&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jun 7 — 25, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/07/06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/07/06/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/07/06/featured-cdhweb-embed_hu401108991c7d5a326e154ec8d24d8d4e_160474_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="692"/>
&lt;p>This past iteration, we split our focus between PPA and CDH web. On PPA, we worked on adding support for importing Gale/ECCO content. For CDH web, we worked on the first charter for CDH web, to articulate the roles and responsibilities and prioritize for the next phases of work (chartering is not reflected in the GitHub issues reported here). We extended the iteration to three weeks, to work around an off week for June 28 — July 2 (CDH staff R&amp;amp;D week).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling velocity is 17 points, with 15 points accepted in this iteration and 28 issues closed. This is higher than we might expect, but due to the longer 3-week iteration and also a number of chores and duplicate issues that were cleaned up on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made substantial progress on support for importing and searching across Gale/ECCO content alongside existing HathiTrust content. We also completed design work to update PPA display to handle multiple sources and different item types (excerpts and book sections).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-web">CDH web&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We fixed a couple of small bugs, and adjusted the affiliates and students page so that the new Data Fellows would be included. We also ported a custom embed finder from the Shakespeare and Company codebase to allow embedding dynamic content in blog posts and other wagtail pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We fixed a few small bugs that were found in production after the release and data import, and also completed a few chores and small stories to help with data work in the new interface, including adding very simple date fields and a script to import Fragment image and IIIF urls from a CSV.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-cdhweb-embed.png"
alt="Screenshot of dynamic content embedded in a CDH web post; see the essay for the interactive version."/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of dynamic content embedded in a CDH web post; see the &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/updates/2021/07/01/old-project-new-database-geniza/">essay&lt;/a> for the interactive version.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 24 — Jun 4, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/06/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/06/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/06/07/featured_geniza_prelim_search_hua1ec862dfc1584070957db372a1cd828_91060_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="508"/>
&lt;p>Our focus this iteration was on Geniza work as we finished out the second phase of work and created our first production release: we successfully migrated the Princeton Geniza Project metadata from a Google Sheets spreadsheet into the new relational database!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work leading up to the 0.3 release included further refinements to the editor/translator data import, various CSV exports for content editors and a feed to keep the current public PGP site up to date with changes made in the database. After the release, we did some follow up work to make some adjustments to the admin interface, address a couple of bugs found after the code went to production, and a very preliminary version of the public document search. Those updates have not yet been deployed, and another set of updates are still in progress or awaiting testing, so some wrap-up work will continue into the next iteration. As part of wrapping up this phase of work, we closed a number of experimental tasks on GitHub that are no longer relevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story points trend for the last two iterations (18 points each, rolling velocity of 15) shows the kind of momentum that is possible at this phase of a project, but also reflects the staffing adjustments we made to ensure we met our deadline to finish the metadata migration before the end of May.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured_geniza_prelim_search.png"
alt="Screenshot of the preliminary version of the Geniza public search"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the preliminary version of the Geniza public search&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 10 — 21, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/05/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/05/24/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/05/24/featured-ppa-focus-styles_hu6c4290d7aabc7625ef86de2acc93b221_73095_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="291"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed 18 development points on Geniza as we work towards a first release and migrating the metadata from the spreadsheet to the new relational database. We also completed a smattering of bugfixes and chores as part of planned maintenance work, and one unplanned bugfix. The 18 point total brings our rolling velocity up to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notable development work completed this iteration are related to scholarship record data import and editing functionality, as well as handling demerge on import and improving the admin document search. For design, we made progress on content pages, updates to the auto-layout in Figma, and progress on typefaces, even though no design issues were closed this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-prosody-archive">Princeton Prosody Archive&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Planned maintenance work on PPA included an update to switch out the frontend library Semantic UI, which is no longer being maintained, for the community fork, Fomantic UI. The other notable change is an improvement to hover and focus styles, for better accessibility and consistency.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released minor update with a trivial bugfix to address something we missed in the 3.0 release, so that content editors can customize the preview text displayed for blog posts. We also closed a few more bug issues that are no longer relevant now that we&amp;rsquo;ve switched from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-footnote-transcription.png"
alt="Screenshot of Geniza admin interface for a scholarship record footnote with transcription"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Geniza admin interface for a scholarship record footnote with transcription&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-ppa-focus-styles.png"
alt="Screenshot of PPA archive search showing new focus styles for improved accessibility"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of PPA archive search showing new focus styles for improved accessibility&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 26 — May 7, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/05/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/05/10/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/05/10/featured-geniza-document-detail_hu2f9aee1d5d69e0ebe1a73f8355b78149_2751041_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="441"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed 10 development points for a rolling velocity of 8. Our primary focus was on Princeton Geniza Project, but we did a small amount of planned work on the CDH website, ansible deploy scripts, and a very small amount of unplanned work on Shakespeare and Company Project to fix a time-sensitive bug.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Accepted development work consists of a preliminary document detail page for the public site and admin editing enhancements, including a footnote count for the source list in admin, a way to edit and link to documents on the fragment edit view, and a certainty flag for TextBlocks to handle potential joins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Completed design work includes a decision on document titles for detail pages as well as search and browse, revisions to the document detail page based on the initial implementation, and completed wireframes for sort and filter on search for all screens.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed planned maintenance and released version 3.0.2 — this update removes all mezzanine dependencies and resets database migrations, making it possible for the site to finally be upgraded to newer versions of django and wagtail. This also resolved a bug in the 3.0 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The bugfix release was a small change to address a limitation on the 100 years twitter code — it did not handle subscriptions and renewals with no known duration, as revealed by a tweet on Monday. The bugfix was out in time to handle the next occurrence on Friday.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-document-detail.png"
alt="Screenshot of preliminary document detail page for Princeton Geniza Project"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of preliminary document detail page for Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 12 — 23, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/04/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/04/26/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/04/26/featured-pgp-change-history_hu9f9e5ad30b3f4175f68327304d5cb344_33364_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="123"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed 11 development points for a rolling velocity of 19, still coming down from the massive number of points closed three iterations ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made more improvements to the data import, fixing Language+Script mapping based on the new display names and resolving all previously unhandled languages, and most notably parsing history input information (names and dates) into structured django log entries to preserve the known edit history of PGP documents. We also completed preliminary work on footnote models for linking scholarship records to documents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For design, wireframes for cluster view browse and search results pages for all screens (desktop, tablet, mobile) were all completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We fixed a couple more bugs in the 3.0 version and released a planned 3.0.1 cleanup release to remove exodus code specific to the shift to wagtail. This is a necessary step to removing mezzanine, which will finally let us upgrade to newer versions of Dljango and python.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-pgp-change-history.png"
alt="Screenshot of change history for a test imported document showing historic changes"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of change history for a test imported document showing historic changes&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="pgp-first-last-edits.png"
alt="Screenshot of earliest and most recent changes for a test import document, shown on the document dit form"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of earliest and most recent changes for a test import document, shown on the document dit form&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 29 — Apr 9, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/04/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/04/12/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/04/12/featured-sco_map_essay_hu5a7f23e9c9277fbc92bf6da0a0ea5ae8_1305134_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="331"/>
&lt;p>The development points for this iteration were quite low (only 4 points), but our rolling velocity continues to be unnusually high (26 points) based on the last two iterations, which were included an enormous amount of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on the design velocidy graph, we might be finding a new rhythm with design work on our new adjusted design schedule.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finally finished and deployed the 3.0 release, migrating content from the outdated and unsupported Mezzanine to Wagtail. This iteration included a few issues to close out the release, deploying the update and running the exodus script to convert content, and then some bugfixes and clean up work for a planned 3.0.1 release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we finished some smaller work related to the database and admin sorting, and made progress on document detail designs. Multiple larger features were delivered late in the iteration, which didn&amp;rsquo;t give enough time for testing to be completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low points this iteration may in part be a result of successful acceptance testing last iteration, which meant we had no in-progress work at the start of the iteration, as we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past. Rolling velocity will smooth out the volatility here, as intended.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company">Shakespeare and Company&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We had a small release for S&amp;amp;co with one bug fix (tested last iteration) and an enhancement adapted from PPA, to support embedding dynamic content (such as the map below) in Analysis essays and other site content pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-sco_map_essay.png"
alt="Screenshot of the dynamic map embedded in the newly published essay on the Literary Right Bank on Shakespeare and Company Project"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the dynamic map embedded in the newly published essay on the &lt;a href="https://shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/analysis/2021/04/literary-right-bank/">Literary Right Bank&lt;/a> on Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 15 — 29, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/29/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/29/featured-cdhweb-page-history_hu3ccb080dc3feaf0cdac3a01620139301_83318_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="359"/>
&lt;p>The points and total number of issues closed for the last iteration is quite high — 42 points total, 25 for cdhweb and 17 for geniza, which results in a rolling velocity of 27. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think this is a sign that we&amp;rsquo;re gaining momentum on geniza work, but suspect that the high numbers are due to work that rolled over from the last iteration and a significant push to finish cdhweb 3.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on building out the database and importing existing data. New features include a document suppression feature, automatic tracking of historic shelfmarks, and a &amp;ldquo;needs review&amp;rdquo; field where content editors can add notes about problems or questions in the data that are used to create a queue of records with problems to be addressed. We also finished testing on data import issues from previous iterations, most notably preliminary document &amp;amp; fragment import.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed features related to blog migration and managing site menus and navigation via wagtail, and resolved a number of longstanding bugs that are no longer an issue now that the site is on wagtail instead of mezzanine. There are only a few small issues rolling over for final testing and review before the 3.0 release can be created and deployed production.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-awaiting-review.png"
alt="Screenshot of Geniza admin interface with new awaiting review feature"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Geniza admin interface with new awaiting review feature&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="cdhweb-wagtail-recents.png"
alt="Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing recent edits, based on page history events"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing recent edits, based on page history events&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-cdhweb-page-history.png"
alt="Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing page history with migration event"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of cdhweb wagtail interface showing page history with migration event&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 1 — 12, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/15/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/15/featured-geniza-tagnetwork-detail_hu92be73fe69a8d7f2888c82f5551e2265_5116992_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="400"/>
&lt;p>Rolling velocity for this iteration increased from about 10 points to about 15 points, largely due to a substantial chunk of CDH website user stories that completed the testing process together after multiple iterations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH Website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed testing on a large set of issues that have been rolling over through multiple iterations, including major changes to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Events&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People &amp;amp; Profiles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project, Grants, and Grant Memberships&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Work is still in progress on content management updates for Blog Posts, the last major module to migrate as part of the v3.0 update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed the admin management interface for Documents, the primary model in the Geniza database. In addition, we added new functionality to track where and how often languages &amp;amp; scripts are used by Documents, including provision for probable or uncertain language identification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To support upcoming functionality for de-merging composite documents, we added an option to &amp;ldquo;clone&amp;rdquo; Documents with a record of the process stored in the database. We also experimented with clustering tags assigned to documents in order to start finding patterns in the data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the design side, we completed revisions to the sitemap diagram and created a low-fidelity mockup of the public view for Documents to spark discussion on content structure and hierarchy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four user stories related to the interface and data import process for Fragments are still in-progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-tagnetwork-detail.png"
alt="Visualization of tag network generated from Geniza document tags"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Visualization of tag network generated from Geniza document tags&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-document-admin.png"
alt="Screenshot of administrative interface for Geniza document database"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of administrative interface for Geniza document database&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 15 - 26, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/03/01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/03/01/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/03/01/featured-geniza-language-admin_huddcbf6b09e7aaa0ac1befe273c5630ef_107246_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="479"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we continued to make progress on building out the new relational database for the Geniza project and importing existing data from spreadsheets. Database structure, admin interface, and data import for languages &amp;amp; scripts are complete; data import for library collections are complete but the admin editing story is not yet complete due to changes in the requirements. Database structure, and admin interface for documents and fragments are underway and far enough along to share a list of questions and necessary data work for the import to proceed, but have not yet been delivered for testing. In terms of design work, issues were delivered with proposed sitemap for sign off and mockups for the structure and content of the document detail page, but neither were closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Progress on the CDH website migration continues, and while some testing took place this iteration no stories were accepted and completed. There are now eight issues (24 story points) awaiting testing, up from the seven issues (18 points) reported at the beginning of the end of the last iteration. This could be due to a new acceptance tester learning the process combined with complicated issues, but it raises concerns, especially since some issues have already been tested more than once and are not yet accepted.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-language-admin.png"
alt="Screenshot of Django admin interface for Languages and Scripts in the test Geniza database"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Django admin interface for Languages and Scripts in the test Geniza database&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 1 - 13, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/02/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/15/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we closed a significant number of issues for the Geniza project; the completed development work was all related to prototypes from the first phase (IIIF images with transcription, experimenting with eScriptorium, and two stories for a multilingual prototype). We also closed two design issues related to the sitemap &amp;amp; site flow diagram and the holistic search. We started implementing the new Geniza database and admin site, but have not yet delivered any issues for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on the CDH web development, but testing was blocked since we lost our previous acceptance tester. Seven issues (18 story points) are in &amp;ldquo;development complete&amp;rdquo; status, and a new tester has been identified and will be trained this iteration, so hope to see significant progress there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rolling development velocity of &lt;strong>8.7&lt;/strong> is plausible, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say how accurate that will be as we move from prototyping into database development and data import scripts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 11 - 22, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/02/01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/02/01/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/02/01/featured-geniza-sitemap_hu460cea3d9fdce17d8ee1dbdbd941b1b8_1071960_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="207"/>
&lt;p>Last iteration we made substantial progress on the cdhweb &amp;ldquo;exodus&amp;rdquo; from mezzanine to wagtail: features related to editing and &amp;ldquo;exodizing&amp;rdquo; content pages and uploaded images have been tested and accepted, and more work is underway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active development was paused on Geniza, but design work continued on a revised sitemap / site flow diagram for the new PGP site and reports to share information from usability testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Development work on Shakespeare and Company Project was to support updated data exports; version 1.1 of the datasets were published January 29th. The parasolr hotfix was due to a problem identified in prepping the Shakespeare and Company Project release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also deployed version 3.5 of PPA to production at the beginning of this iteration (the release updates and prep were completed before the holidays), which enabled the team to finally add new content from HathiTrust. (Read a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ProsodyArchive/status/1349391218296434692">twitter thread of new works added&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-sitemap.png"
alt="Sitemap/site flow diagram for new Princeton Geniza Project site (view on Figma)"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Sitemap/site flow diagram for new Princeton Geniza Project site (&lt;a href="https://www.figma.com/file/HpGBOZi9lO8B3nCAx3d4Fj/Princeton-Geniza?node-id=415%3A2">view on Figma&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Version 1.1 of &lt;a href="https://dataspace.princeton.edu/handle/88435/dsp01fx719q532">Shakespeare and Company Project Datasets&lt;/a>, including updated readmes and change logs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 14, 2020 - Jan 8, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/01/11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/01/11/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Due to the holidays and planned vacations, we decided to take a long iteration spanning from December 14th to the end of the first week in January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We spent the majority of the time on maintenance and addressing some technical debt. The CDH website was successfully moved from Research Computing and a MySQL database to its new home on a PUL VM and running on the PUL Postgresql database server. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on CDH web 3.0, which involves the transition (which we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to call &amp;ldquo;exodus&amp;rdquo; to avoid confusion with &amp;ldquo;migration&amp;rdquo;) from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration we also finally successfully addressed the problem in PPA for adding new HathiTrust content. The release was tagged December 22nd, along with a supporting release of parasolr, but rather than deploy an update right before the holidays, it was held. That release will go into production early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu">CDH website&lt;/a> v2.8.1 update was largely an infrastructural one, so there is little that is visible to display and we expect and want it to look it exactly as before.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>One visible change: emoji are now supported! See &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/updates/2020/11/18/dating-problems-ask-princeton-geniza-project-team/">Marina&amp;rsquo;s post on dates and dating&lt;/a> to see the emojis she originally included, which were not supported on the previous version of the site.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 30 - Dec 12, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/12/nov-30-dec-12-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/12/nov-30-dec-12-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we paused active software development on the Geniza project, although design research and work on sitemap and continued, along with planning for the next phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We shifted development efforts to an infrastructure migration for the CDH website and planning for CDH web 3.0, which consists of a major migration to move content management functionality from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was also development effort on Shakespeare and Company Project with the main goal of generating updated dataset exports in January, although we did address a handful of small bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration we also had PPA work become unblocked: the revised solution for adding new content from HathiTrust was blocked by errors with rsync, which were finally resolved this iteration, so the feature was finally delivered for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because the work this iteration was largely focused on infrastructure and data, there is nothing visual to demo. The high number of development issues closed relative to points reflects the number of bugs and chores closed, and also reflects the fact that much of the work for CDH web remains in-progress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 16 - 27, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/30/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/30/featured-geniza-tags_hue9cb7085157941caad4966623a815cc8_192671_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="120"/>
&lt;p>This was our last scheduled iteration for working on Geniza prototyping,
so we made a push to finish as much of that work as possible before we switch to other things. Work completed includes a report of name extracted from metadata descriptions, to help with data work and future data migrations; an experimental tag filter that allows the user to select how tags are combined; and a keyword search on the experimental holistic search (the latter two will be used for usability testing). We also delivered for testing a simplistic implementation of TEI transcriptions converted to IIIF annotations and displayed in the Mirador 3 viewer, and finished work on a django prototype with internationalization. Unfortunately, complications with the deploy of the second prorotype meant we were unable to deliver that work for testing last week before the Thanksgiving holiday. No design tasks were marked as completed on GitHub, and the design work at this phase is still largely UX research; but there are in-progress design tasks for document detail page, holistic search results, and preliminary sitemap that we expect to close in this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration also includes 5 points from a CDH web feature that was completed in the previous iteration, and a CDH web release with updates completed in the last iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-geniza-tags.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-cluster-search.png"
alt="Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 2 - 14, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/16/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/16/featured-cluster-prototype_huc4dfd2b8c37a1e52c03ddc05f78843df_330385_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="479"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made substantial progress on our Geniza search prototyping, most notably implementing the first two steps towards a prototype of the holistic search interface that Gissoo has been designing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some updates and fixed some bugs for CDH web, towards a maintenance release that will go out early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-cluster-prototype.png"
alt="Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 19 - 31, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/02/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/02/featured-startwords-weaving-interface_hu6f24b4b9c5af428670450e95cc68919c_571393_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="335"/>
&lt;p>Very pleased to report that this past iteration we finally published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/">Issue One of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. The velocity charts below reflect the effort to get this out the door, including completion of design and implementation on an experimental piece and a large amount of work to finish converting the long &amp;ldquo;Data Beyond Vision&amp;rdquo; essay and related snippets to markdown, and to finish custom styles for the essay, including PDF styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also continuing our work on prototyping and data exploration for the Geniza project; this iteration saw our first two search prototype stories accepted. We also published the charter for the Geniza research partnership; it&amp;rsquo;s available at &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re also continuing to make progress switching our GitHub repositories to a default branch of &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong>. In the last iteration, we updated the Ansible deploys to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> by default for production deploys, and updated all projects with a production deploy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-startwords-weaving-interface.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Startwords experimental Weaving as Interface piece"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> experimental &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/weaving-as-interface/">Weaving as Interface&lt;/a> piece&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="startwords-dbv-pdf.png"
alt="Screenshot from the Startwords PDF for Data Beyond Vision"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot from the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> PDF for &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 5 - 15, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/19/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/10/19/featured-dbv-visuals_hu5a4dd102ce4f0bcbe542030242904bd8_198769_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="207"/>
&lt;p>Last iteration we put a lot of time and effort into Startwords as we get close to our issue 1 deadline and launch date, although that&amp;rsquo;s not reflected in the number of tickets closed on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on Geniza planning and prototyping. That isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly evident from the issues closed, but that&amp;rsquo;s in part because we were hung up on getting the hostname for the new test server and acceptance testing only started at the end of the iteration. Design work at this point is primarily research, which we have not been tracking on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some minor improvements to our ansible deploys and dev/design site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured-dbv-visuals.png"
alt="Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in Startwords"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="dbv-icons.png"
alt="Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for Startwords"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="geniza-search-prototype.png"
alt="Geniza search prototype"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 21 - Oct 2, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/05/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration marked our official start of work on the Geniza research partnership, now that the charter has been signed. We made progress on data modeling and a preliminary search prototype, but since none of those tasks have been completed they aren&amp;rsquo;t reflected in the issues and points below. We also saw a lot of activity on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, as the team makes the push to complete remaining functionality and styles needed for the project launch. We also made progress on PPA maintenance and bug fixes, although the fixes have not yet been released to production, and one bug fix is ready for testing but blocked waiting on HathiTrust restoring rsync dataset access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> article image styles — see on &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision draft article&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/notfound">404 page designs&lt;/a> have been implemented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://parasolr.readthedocs.io/en/develop/gettingstarted.html">Basic &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; documentation for parasolr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 7 - 18, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/21/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration included work to complete cdh-web version 2.7, which consisted of maintenance upgrades and a few helpful features for fall; maintenance and bug fixes on PPA, including a refactor to use in-house Solr library parasolr, removing a dependency on a forked, unmaintained SolrClient; and continued progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major work not reflected here includes the final revisions on charter for the CDH/Geniza research partnership, which was signed and approved today, and improved planning and documentation for the steps to close out a project when a research partnership grant ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CDH web &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/people/affiliates/">affiliates page now includes staff, such as PUL librarians directing data curation projects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CDH web events can now be designated as virtual, and take an optional URL for joining the virtual event&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 24 - Sep 4, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/08/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/08/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/09/08/featured_startwords_404design_huff12e89c7eb4ae2479e06a3c7a794ddf_79450_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="379"/>
&lt;p>The last iteration we continued to spend time on project maintenance and updates. Closed issues on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> and the pucas release are continuing and closing out work from the previous iterations. Active work this iteration that is incomplete and not reflected in the closed tickets include django/mezzanine upgrades for cdhweb, and refactoring PPA to remove an outdated SolrClient dependency and use parasolr instead. We also have now migrated our first repositories to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> as the production branch name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last iteration we also wrote a new &lt;em>limited support agreement&lt;/em>, which was adapted and simplified from the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3359203">&amp;ldquo;Built by CDH&amp;rdquo; Long Term Service Agreement&lt;/a> in order to offer minimal support for the &lt;a href="https://pemm.cdh.princeton.edu/">PEMM Incipit Search Tool&lt;/a> for a limited term (1 year, renewable for a second year). The limited support agreement for PEMM goes into effect today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/">New dev/design site&lt;/a> (still in progress)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.figma.com/file/MEt3gfKX4N3WTLPbLGBbGC/Startwords?node-id=1104%3A3516">404 error design&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Articles now have image styles with automatic derivatives for different size screens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>&lt;img src="featured_startwords_404design.png"
alt="Screenshot of new 404 page design for Startwords"/>&lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of new 404 page design for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 10 - 20, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/24/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Not a lot of development work reported on GitHub because the primary team focus continues to be planning the new Research Partnership project. This iteration also included time spent on two internal project retrospectives (Shakespeare and Company Project, PEMM) and a CDH Retreat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active development work included progress on PPA bugfixes (delivered for testing but not complete) and minor maintenance updates to django-pucas (removing support for python 2.7 to fix the a failing master build, in preparation for migrating from master to main).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The long list of &amp;ldquo;wontfix&amp;rdquo; issues in the mep-django is a result of cleaning up GitHub for Shakespeare and Company Project to close issues that were postponed or wishlisted on the way to a 1.0 release and we no longer plan to work on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 20 - Aug 7, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/10/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Three week iteration due to multiple team member week-long vacations. Less development work than usual because the primary team focus has been on planning the new Research Partnership project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jun 29 - Jul 17, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/07/21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/07/21/</guid><description>
&lt;p>PEMM release with final updates to close out grant year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shakespeare and Company Project updates related to publishing 1.0 data exports; includes 100 years twitter bot code&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jun 15 — 26, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/06/30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/30/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Lots of progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, but no official release until Issue 1 is ready.
PEMM release put off until this iteration since only one feature was completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demo">Demo&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="_startwords_">&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Scrollable contextual notes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/about/">We have an about page!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/the-body-as-data/">Pull quote!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/stack-shakespeare-and-company-membership-activities/">Our first short piece!!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/#-">Amazing pit bar&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Princeton-CDH/startwords/issues/22#issuecomment-651201652">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>