<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dev/Design @ CDH – Iteration Reports</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/</link><description>Recent content in Iteration Reports on Dev/Design @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/blog/iteration-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: December 14, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/12/december-14-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/12/december-14-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration we paused active software development on the Geniza project, although design research and work on sitemap and continued, along with planning for the next phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We shifted development efforts to an infrastructure migration for the CDH website and planning for CDH web 3.0, which consists of a major migration to move content management functionality from Mezzanine to Wagtail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was also development effort on Shakespeare and Company Project with the main goal of generating updated dataset exports in January, although we did address a handful of small bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because the work this iteration was largely focused on infrastructure and data, there is nothing visual to demo. The high number of development issues closed relative to points reflects the number of bugs and chores closed, and also reflects the fact that much of the work for CDH web remains in-progress.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 30, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-30-2020/featured-geniza-tags_hue9cb7085157941caad4966623a815cc8_192671_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="120"/>
&lt;p>This was our last scheduled iteration for working on Geniza prototyping,
so we made a push to finish as much of that work as possible before we switch to other things. Work completed includes a report of name extracted from metadata descriptions, to help with data work and future data migrations; an experimental tag filter that allows the user to select how tags are combined; and a keyword search on the experimental holistic search (the latter two will be used for usability testing). We also delivered for testing a simplistic implementation of TEI transcriptions converted to IIIF annotations and displayed in the Mirador 3 viewer, and finished work on a django prototype with internationalization. Unfortunately, complications with the deploy of the second prorotype meant we were unable to deliver that work for testing last week before the Thanksgiving holiday. No design tasks were marked as completed on GitHub, and the design work at this phase is still largely UX research; but there are in-progress design tasks for document detail page, holistic search results, and preliminary sitemap that we expect to close in this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This iteration also includes 5 points from a CDH web feature that was completed in the previous iteration, and a CDH web release with updates completed in the last iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-geniza-tags.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new tags filter in the Geniza search prototype; searchers can choose how tags should be combined&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-cluster-search.png"
alt="Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of keyword search results the Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 16, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-16-2020/featured-cluster-prototype_huc4dfd2b8c37a1e52c03ddc05f78843df_330385_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="479"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made substantial progress on our Geniza search prototyping, most notably implementing the first two steps towards a prototype of the holistic search interface that Gissoo has been designing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some updates and fixed some bugs for CDH web, towards a maintenance release that will go out early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-cluster-prototype.png"
alt="Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the experimental Geniza cluster search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: November 2, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/11/november-2-2020/featured-startwords-weaving-interface_hu6f24b4b9c5af428670450e95cc68919c_571393_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="335"/>
&lt;p>Very pleased to report that this past iteration we finally published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/">Issue One of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. The velocity charts below reflect the effort to get this out the door, including completion of design and implementation on an experimental piece and a large amount of work to finish converting the long &amp;ldquo;Data Beyond Vision&amp;rdquo; essay and related snippets to markdown, and to finish custom styles for the essay, including PDF styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also continuing our work on prototyping and data exploration for the Geniza project; this iteration saw our first two search prototype stories accepted. We also published the charter for the Geniza research partnership; it&amp;rsquo;s available at &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4081714&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re also continuing to make progress switching our GitHub repositories to a default branch of &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong>. In the last iteration, we updated the Ansible deploys to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> by default for production deploys, and updated all projects with a production deploy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-startwords-weaving-interface.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Startwords experimental Weaving as Interface piece"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> experimental &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/weaving-as-interface/">Weaving as Interface&lt;/a> piece&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="startwords-dbv-pdf.png"
alt="Screenshot from the Startwords PDF for Data Beyond Vision"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot from the &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> PDF for &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: October 19th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/10/october-19th-2020/featured-dbv-visuals_hu5a4dd102ce4f0bcbe542030242904bd8_198769_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="207"/>
&lt;p>Last iteration we put a lot of time and effort into Startwords as we get close to our issue 1 deadline and launch date, although that&amp;rsquo;s not reflected in the number of tickets closed on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on Geniza planning and prototyping. That isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly evident from the issues closed, but that&amp;rsquo;s in part because we were hung up on getting the hostname for the new test server and acceptance testing only started at the end of the iteration. Design work at this point is primarily research, which we have not been tracking on GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made some minor improvements to our ansible deploys and dev/design site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-dbv-visuals.png"
alt="Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Custom styles for Data Beyond Vision essay in &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="dbv-icons.png"
alt="Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Revised icons for Data Beyond Vision essay for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="geniza-search-prototype.png"
alt="Geniza search prototype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search prototype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: October 5th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/10/october-5th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/10/october-5th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration marked our official start of work on the Geniza research partnership, now that the charter has been signed. We made progress on data modeling and a preliminary search prototype, but since none of those tasks have been completed they aren&amp;rsquo;t reflected in the issues and points below. We also saw a lot of activity on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, as the team makes the push to complete remaining functionality and styles needed for the project launch. We also made progress on PPA maintenance and bug fixes, although the fixes have not yet been released to production, and one bug fix is ready for testing but blocked waiting on HathiTrust restoring rsync dataset access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> article image styles — see on &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Data Beyond Vision draft article&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/notfound">404 page designs&lt;/a> have been implemented&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://parasolr.readthedocs.io/en/develop/gettingstarted.html">Basic &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; documentation for parasolr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: September 21st, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/september-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/september-21st-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This iteration included work to complete cdh-web version 2.7, which consisted of maintenance upgrades and a few helpful features for fall; maintenance and bug fixes on PPA, including a refactor to use in-house Solr library parasolr, removing a dependency on a forked, unmaintained SolrClient; and continued progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Major work not reflected here includes the final revisions on charter for the CDH/Geniza research partnership, which was signed and approved today, and improved planning and documentation for the steps to close out a project when a research partnership grant ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>CDH web &lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/people/affiliates/">affiliates page now includes staff, such as PUL librarians directing data curation projects&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CDH web events can now be designated as virtual, and take an optional URL for joining the virtual event&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: September 8th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2020/09/september-8th-2020/featured_startwords_404design_huff12e89c7eb4ae2479e06a3c7a794ddf_79450_640x0_resize_catmullrom_2.png" width="640" height="379"/>
&lt;p>The last iteration we continued to spend time on project maintenance and updates. Closed issues on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> and the pucas release are continuing and closing out work from the previous iterations. Active work this iteration that is incomplete and not reflected in the closed tickets include django/mezzanine upgrades for cdhweb, and refactoring PPA to remove an outdated SolrClient dependency and use parasolr instead. We also have now migrated our first repositories to use &lt;strong>main&lt;/strong> as the production branch name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last iteration we also wrote a new &lt;em>limited support agreement&lt;/em>, which was adapted and simplified from the &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3359203">&amp;ldquo;Built by CDH&amp;rdquo; Long Term Service Agreement&lt;/a> in order to offer minimal support for the &lt;a href="https://pemm.cdh.princeton.edu/">PEMM Incipit Search Tool&lt;/a> for a limited term (1 year, renewable for a second year). The limited support agreement for PEMM goes into effect today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://princeton-cdh.github.io/">New dev/design site&lt;/a> (still in progress)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.figma.com/file/MEt3gfKX4N3WTLPbLGBbGC/Startwords?node-id=1104%3A3516">404 error design&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Articles now have image styles with automatic derivatives for different size screens&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured_startwords_404design.png"
alt="Screenshot of new 404 page design for Startwords"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of new 404 page design for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: August 24th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/august-24th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/august-24th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Not a lot of development work reported on GitHub because the primary team focus continues to be planning the new Research Partnership project. This iteration also included time spent on two internal project retrospectives (Shakespeare and Company Project, PEMM) and a CDH Retreat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Active development work included progress on PPA bugfixes (delivered for testing but not complete) and minor maintenance updates to django-pucas (removing support for python 2.7 to fix the a failing master build, in preparation for migrating from master to main).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The long list of &amp;ldquo;wontfix&amp;rdquo; issues in the mep-django is a result of cleaning up GitHub for Shakespeare and Company Project to close issues that were postponed or wishlisted on the way to a 1.0 release and we no longer plan to work on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: August 10th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/08/august-10th-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/08/august-10th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Three week iteration due to multiple team member week-long vacations. Less development work than usual because the primary team focus has been on planning the new Research Partnership project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: July 21st, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/07/july-21st-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/07/july-21st-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>PEMM release with final updates to close out grant year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shakespeare and Company Project updates related to publishing 1.0 data exports; includes 100 years twitter bot code&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: June 30th, 2020</title><link>/blog/2020/06/june-30th-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020/06/june-30th-2020/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Lots of progress on &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>, but no official release until Issue 1 is ready.
PEMM release put off until this iteration since only one feature was completed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demo">Demo&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="_startwords_">&lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/">Scrollable contextual notes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/about/">We have an about page!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/the-body-as-data/">Pull quote!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/stack-shakespeare-and-company-membership-activities/">Our first short piece!!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/1/data-beyond-vision/#-">Amazing pit bar&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Princeton-CDH/startwords/issues/22#issuecomment-651201652">PDF&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>