<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Software @ CDH – Iteration Reports</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/</link><description>Recent content in Iteration Reports on Research Software @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/iteration-reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: Apr 29 - May 8, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/05/09/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/05/09/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This marked the second iteration of the new RSE team cycle, with a 8 day development sprint, followed by 2 days of R&amp;amp;D. The RSE team was focused on the PPA, as well as wrapping up some maintenance issues that carried over from last sprint.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="releases">Releases&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The team wrapped up two major releases this week. We started the iteration with the release of the Wagtail upgrade for CDH web ahead of the technical phase of the website redesign. And we closed the iteration with the release of version 1.6 and 1.6.1 of Shakespeare and Company, which closed out a cluster of issues around improving data imports and exports.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Springload redesign is moving forward with the implementation of the website redesign: &lt;a href="https://github.com/springload/cdh-web/">https://github.com/springload/cdh-web/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For the main PPA application, the focus this iteration was on the integration with EEBO and addressing the shift in Gale&amp;rsquo;s approach to serving images. Both are underway and moving forward smoothly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the NLP project, worked continued on assessing and preparing the corpus for analysis, as well as initial planning for the creating of annotations. Laure completed the evaluation of the existing OCR, with a recommendation to re-OCR the text from Gale. The resulting data on detected languages also proved useful as a way to filter pages and to identify where the OCR error rate is likely high.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="aerial-archival-photography">Aerial Archival Photography&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We continue to make progress with assessing the work completed by Microsoft. We have a copy of the package developed for Prof. Kreike&amp;rsquo;s data. Next iteration we will have a call with the Microsoft to clarify any questions / procedures and attempt to run the package on Princeton hardware.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="maintenace-projects">Maintenace Projects&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We continue to support and consult on the Geniza project, particularly around issues of search and solr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bug with Ansible Tower was addressed by PUL, which clears the way to set up the deploy of our major web applications (CDH Web, Geniza, S&amp;amp;Co) through this interface. This will improve our workflow for collaborating with external partners and contractors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The issues with timeouts continues, and PUL has added datadog to the production applications so that we can get better visibility on what is happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in preparation for next week, the VMs for the Derrida Archive are ready to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the process front, we are working with GitHub Projects for managing each iteration and learning to use the built in charts, as well as how to export data from Projects. Jeri found a script for exporting a project board to a CSV, which we can use to capture our historical data (&lt;a href="https://github.com/fiedl/github-project-to-csv)">https://github.com/fiedl/github-project-to-csv)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="writing">Writing&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The long-awaited article-proofs arrived for the Shakespeare and Company cluster, which Rebecca was able to review, as well as finalize the corresponding replication code. In addition, she submitted the &amp;ldquo;Trust Your Code&amp;rdquo; article for publication; and submitted to the DH Mini Conference on Simulating Risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="upcoming-priorities">Upcoming Priorities&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Looking ahead, we will be focused next on completing the archive of Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins (ahead of the server being shut down), interfacing with Microsoft regarding their object detection pipeline, completing the itegration with EEBO data on PPA, and determining the work plan for identifying poems in the PPA data. We are also ramping up our preparations for the London RSE site visits and the DARIAH conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Interactive figures for the Shakespeare and Company article: &lt;a href="https://viz.shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/">https://viz.shakespeareandco.princeton.edu/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2024/05/09/2024-05-10-Iteration2Points.png"
alt="Total Story Points at the end of Iteration 2: 34 points queued; 22 points completed"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Total Story Points at the end of Iteration 2: 34 points queued; 22 points completed&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 15 - Apr 26, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/04/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/04/29/</guid><description>
&lt;p>add summary paragraphs(s) about the iteration&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>add demo links or screenshots&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-###.png"
alt=" "/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>&lt;h2 id="heading">&lt;/h2>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 1 - Apr 12, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/04/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/04/15/</guid><description>
&lt;p>add summary paragraphs(s) about the iteration&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>add demo links or screenshots&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-###.png"
alt=" "/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>&lt;h2 id="heading">&lt;/h2>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 18 - Mar 29, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/04/01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/04/01/</guid><description>
&lt;p>It was another busy iteration at the CDH. There was a lot of activity on the PPA core issues, as well as initial planning and progress for the NLP part of the research collaboration. Our other active projects saw smaller movements as they either ramp up or down. We also had a number of meetings, internal and with external collaborators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Worked with Mary to fix the save-as-new issue and new excerpt save problems&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Helped with rescoping and planning; hathi rsync work now complete for current needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Implemented script to update excerpt digital page ranges from a CS&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Error handling for page index script when running in &amp;ldquo;expedite&amp;rdquo; mode (based on page counts in db and solr)&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Solr 9 upgrade progress&lt;/li>
&lt;li> named nlp package (corppa!) and did basic setup&lt;/li>
&lt;li> implemented method to filter corpus by source id&lt;/li>
&lt;li>test corpus for small-scale NLP experiments compiled and reviewed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Retested and closed the save-as-new issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cleaned up the EEBO-TCP data work and Lottie is sending that out to Early Modernists for review&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cleaned up the excerpt-range-changes spreadsheet and tested and closed that related issue (unexpected &amp;amp; HUGE!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirmed we have computational analysis permissions on page images and reached out to HathiTrust for additional clarification on specifics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confirmed project metadata with TigerData, they&amp;rsquo;re setting up our space&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Started drafting an &amp;ldquo;Ends of Prosody&amp;rdquo; landing page (I made a placeholder image in Canva!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Groomed the backlog during Q2 planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whiteboarding session with Rebecca and Meredith to set big picture goals and priorities&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developmental editing for the introduction of Poetry&amp;rsquo;s Data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Responded to Gale about the thumbnail thing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reached out to Esme about getting PUL stuff into HT&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Finished testing the excerpts export&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Made a cool flowchart for the rsync workflow and put 3 new related issues into Github and into the rsync epic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cluster bug hotfix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed ad hoc script for collecting HathiTrust version timestamps&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="aap">AAP&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Continue exploring working with the data / setting up my dev environment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scheduled meeting with Kreike team for 4/3&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-rse-projects">Other RSE Projects&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>PGP: reviewed two PRs and provided feedback on a Solr highlighting problem&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GeoTaste: added license to repo, invited Ryan as external collaborator, scheduled 1-1 with Josh&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simrisk: cleanup * merged PR, closed issues, shared custom batch run code on related mesa issue&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-cdh--library--outside">Other CDH / Library / Outside&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>two in-person interviews for PUL devops fellow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>helped with two dhtech code review working group submissions to dhtech miniconf (presentation + workshop)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>attended formal philosophy working group with Lara for presentation on simulating risk work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Springload Meetings
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Tech kickoff meeting for cdhweb redesign&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Website stakeholder interview&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>communicated with Tony Williams (Technology Licensing) to get and document language about Princeton rights + permission to release as open source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>History department recruitment breakfast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attended/participated in Wouter&amp;rsquo;s class on Tuesday and ran the class today&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Attended/co-facilitated the CDH Grad Fellows Meeting&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="meetings">Meetings&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All CDH Exec Meeting All Monday&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Q2 Planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Schmidt Sciences chat&lt;/li>
&lt;li>talk with Francis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="consults">Consults&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data Fellows Consult for Alessia&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consult+ for Fernanda&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consult for Teddy Leane&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other">Other&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Schedule workshop for humanities folks applying for an RSE&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Started process to post job ad for 3rd RSE position&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No demos for this iteration?&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="featured-###.png"
alt=" "/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>&lt;h2 id="heading">&lt;/h2>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 4 - Mar 15, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/03/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/03/18/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Late summary of activity over the first iteration of March. Quite busy despite the reduced work over spring break.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>added Ends of Prosody people to the mailing list&lt;/li>
&lt;li>support of Brian/Laure as they work on excerpts issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inventory of NLP work from the fall (part 2 next week)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>acceptance testing for 4 issues (2/4 closed)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>undergrad wrangling&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collected the version information for the PPA excerpts; found that the vast majority of these volumes were mostly recently updated in 2022+ and that at least in one instance the page range has updated since the excerpts were last checked/verified&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PPA-NLP planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed the fix for the pairtree files issue (#538) and helped resolve the initial failures in testing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Began work on upgrading PPA to Solr 9 (#572)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>made progress on various ppa rsync and excerpt related improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>completed work to recalculate page counts for PPA records&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Revised the NLP portion of the PPA Charter&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Organized Github issues into epics&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Added all of the EEBO-TCP issues into Github&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Tested issues #538 and #567&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Responded to and met with Brian to discuss excerpts fix&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Emailed Jon Stroop who confirmed PUL doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an easy way to submit things to HT, but suggested we follow up with Esme Cowles who has done it before (apparently it&amp;rsquo;s only easy if you&amp;rsquo;re Google or Internet Archive)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="aap">AAP&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li> Obtained Kreike data for local use&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Met with Wangyal to better understand what the shared files are and also gained more general insights about the history of this decades-in-the-making project&lt;/li>
&lt;li> Debriefed with Jeri on my meeting with Wangyal and discussed where this leaves us&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-rse-related">Other RSE-related:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Agile/Scrum/Lean trainings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Work on project closeout ahead of conversations about GeoTaste and Sim Risk&lt;/li>
&lt;li> RSE team overview of how we create pull requests on GitHub (edited) &lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="pm-work">PM work&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>huge headway on Project Design curriculum&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Staff meeting and discussion on new (revamped) programming&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Project Design planning session with Mary&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="other-cdh--university-work">Other CDH / University work&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Got Mallet installed after running into a Java 21 backwards incompatibility issue (David really is the one to thank here)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Began prepping for Wouter&amp;rsquo;s classes on topic modeling (this got delayed by the Mallet issue)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grant applications summaries and write up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lunch, Dinner, Talk, and Dinner with Jo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RSE town hall and start planning for a proposal workshop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>attended spring Research Computing Advisory Group meeting and shared notes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>attended intro to pytorch workshop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>two planning meetings for PUL DEI devops fellowship search committee&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Closing out APRs&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 19 - Mar 1, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/03/04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/03/04/</guid><description>
&lt;p>It was an incredibly productive iteration at the CDH. Here are some highlights across all the different areas we work!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PPA&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Data work
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Completed all Brogan data work for 1925-1928 (99 new works imported)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emailed Joe Marciniak about PUL-HT workflow&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Followed up with Matt Chandler about TigerData (answer: we&amp;rsquo;re in the queue, should be available &amp;ldquo;soon&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Completed checking the IIIF works to see if they are already in PPA / available in HT/ECCO/EEBO (report in #ppa)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Laure’s dev environment got set up (and broken)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HathiTrust excerpt reindexing planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Progress made on PPA hathi/pairtree code&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Kreike&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Access achieved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LOI submitted for larger project&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rereading and mind-mapping&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>SimRisk&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>implemented new convergence logic and wealth chart for simrisk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>generated population category charts across starting distributions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>joined Lara&amp;rsquo;s Philosophy faculty WIP talk&lt;/li>
&lt;li>hypothesis testing / feature evaluation collaboration with preliminary linear regression and a few statistical paired tests on simulating risk batch run data (thanks to Laure for advice!)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Ansible and Deploys&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>not one but 2 PPA patch releases deployed to production&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a little bit of ansible and geotase cleanup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>finishing/merging PRs for playbook consolidation (needed for ansible tower)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>finish &amp;amp; merge geotaste playbook&lt;/li>
&lt;li>geotaste deploy to PUL servers (not yet completed&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>helped fix failing unit tests for s&amp;amp;co import/export code&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>General Support&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Library IT OPS fellowship meeting &amp;amp; 1 phone interview&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DHTech steering committee meeting&lt;/li>
&lt;li>IDS candidate meetings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Joined PGP team for a really productive quarterly check-in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DH code review working group&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>General Strategy and Planning&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Grant reviewing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LOI submitted for 4th RSE line&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initial program development planning for project development and data design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continued APR work&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Science Fiction Group launched&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Guests and Events&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>David Bamman&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Laura McGrath&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simon DeDeo&lt;/li>
&lt;li>LLM reading group&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GeoTaste colloquium&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Simulating Risk with new convergence logic&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 5 - Feb 16, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/02/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/02/19/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Early February was split between wrapping up existing projects, administrative tasks related to annual performance reviews and job descriptions, as well as progress on the current priorities of the PPA and the Kreike project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Shakespeare and Company / GeoTaste, the goal for this iteration was to complete dev work on the GeoTaste application and deploy to the Google Cloud sandbox, as well as finish the export and import commands. Both the import and export commands have open pull requests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Simulating Risk, Lara has requested some data analysis ahead of her talk on the 28th. There is an open pull request waiting for feedback from Lara and a meeting scheduled for the week of the 19th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For Aerial CV, Jeri, Mary, and Laure met with Emmanuel, Wangyal, and Bill (the Time Traveling Trees Team) for a meet-and-greet, as well as early scoping meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For PPA, Mary completed acceptance testing on a number of cluster-bug related issues. We are also waiting on ProQuest for permission related to the content in EEBO.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Potential in-meeting demos:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>import functionality on S&amp;amp;Co&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SimRisk data analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 22 - Feb 2, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/02/05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/02/05/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We made a lot of progress on a number of maintenance tasks this iteration, including some VM upgrades in collaboration with PUL and updating npm packages. We also fixed a glaring bug with image and style displays on the CDH website that was caused by the VM upgrade and the shift to having two machines for load-balancing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Simulating Risk, we completed work on a custom batch-runner for the hawk/dove multi risk attitude game to support large-scale data collection across a wide range of parameter combinations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The larger number of issues closed on the geniza github is due to the project team doing review to clean up and prioritize work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 8 - Jan 19, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/01/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/01/22/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2024/01/22/featured-simrisk-distributions_hua9efb9a17b390a28f553435181609927_214337_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="508"/>
&lt;p>This iteration, on the Simulating Risk project we completed review and acceptance testing of the last planned issues for refining the model to address known flaws and improve robustness, including an option to set initial risk attitudes based on different distributions (random, normal, skewed left or right, bimodal).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On PPA, we did a substantial amount of cleanup on GitHub in preparation for the upcoming work; we closed one chore completed in this iteration, and a few issues that we discovered have been resolved. We closed a large number of old issues (bugs and features both) that we&amp;rsquo;ve decided not to work on since they are not aligned with our priorities for the project. (These are tagged as &amp;ldquo;wontfix&amp;rdquo; and are not reflected in the totals for the iteration, since we did not work on them.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our rolling velocity is &lt;strong>4.3&lt;/strong>, which likely reflects somewhat slow progress on both development and testing due to holidays and other commitments in January, as well as the amount of time we&amp;rsquo;ve been spending on project planning and maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2024/01/22/featured-simrisk-distributions.png"
alt="Screenshot of Simulating Risk hawk/dove game with multiple risk attitudes showing new options or initial distribution of risk attitudes (bimodal distribution pictured)."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Simulating Risk hawk/dove game with multiple risk attitudes showing new options or initial distribution of risk attitudes (bimodal distribution pictured).&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 26 - Jan 6, 2024</title><link>/blog/2024/01/09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2024/01/09/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In the last iteration of 2023, we made significant progress on multiple maintenance projects and completed a major feature on PPA looking towards research planned for 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>PPA&lt;/strong>: We completed work on a new script to export a full-text corpus with page-level content corresponding to what&amp;rsquo;s available on the public site in Solr.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/strong>: We released a new version of the django web application, which included important maintenance updates and some bug fixes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>VM upgrades and load-balancing&lt;/strong>: We worked with PUL to upgrade VMs (from bionic to jammy) and load-balance several of our applications, in both QA/staging and Production environments. As part of this work, we closed out a number of issues related to our ansible deploys. The cdhweb micro release was also related to this upgrade.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Simulating Risk&lt;/strong>: We completed development on the remaining prioritized simulation updates to address flaws or add robustness checks, but due to the holidays they have not yet been reviewed and accepted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2023</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/iteration-reports/2023/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: 2022</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/iteration-reports/2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: 2021</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/iteration-reports/2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: 2020</title><link>/blog/iteration-reports/2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/iteration-reports/2020/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>