<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Software @ CDH – Dev/Design Posts</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Dev/Design Posts on Research Software @ CDH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog: 2023 Q3 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2023/08/2023-q3-schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/08/2023-q3-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 24 - Aug 4, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/08/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/08/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/featured_geotaste_huc96e13bb0fdf14c94c9baa83686ce337_4097083_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="317"/>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re a small team working on multiple projects at once. We made significant progress on the &lt;strong>geotaste&lt;/strong> tool, and work has ramped up in intensity with plans to complete the prototype by the end of August. We also continued making progress on the simulations for the &lt;strong>Simulating Risk&lt;/strong> project, completing a revision to one simulation and a new histogram chart. We also completed some maintenance work on the &lt;strong>CDH website&lt;/strong> to upgrade some dependencies, and released a micro version with those changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/featured_geotaste.png"
alt="Screenshot showing resent progress on the Geotaste mapping tool"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing resent progress on the Geotaste mapping tool&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/08/07/simrisk_histogram.png"
alt="Screenshot showing Simulating Risk interactive Mesa display of the &amp;amp;lsquo;Risky Bet&amp;amp;rsquo; simulation in progress with the new histogram chart."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing Simulating Risk interactive Mesa display of the &amp;lsquo;Risky Bet&amp;rsquo; simulation in progress with the new histogram chart.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 10 - Jul 21, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/07/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/07/24/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/07/24/featured_geotaste_screenshot_hue5233fb2def8d1c4e5e7b219252cd47b_804204_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="391"/>
&lt;p>We extended this iteration to three weeks, to account for team members being away for the DH2023 conference and on vacation. Work in the past iteration included Simulating Risk, GeoTaste, and some maintenance. GeoTaste has been an ongoing project, but we are now starting to track work via GitHub issues and include it iteration reporting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In terms of development, we completed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> points and &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> issues for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>11.3&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an open question how to track design moving forward, now that we no longer have a designer on staff and are working on projects with less dependency on design.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/07/24/featured_geotaste_screenshot.png"
alt="Screenshot showing the current state of the geotaste mapping and comparison tool"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing the current state of the geotaste mapping and comparison tool&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 29 - Jun 9, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/06/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/06/12/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/06/12/featured-lenapetimetree-desktop-zoom_hu68ec7c5dc3e95b8ddece9ebb814d5866_707649_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="352"/>
&lt;p>We made significant progress on the Lenape Timetree project as we worked
to close out the remaining in-scope features, addressed small bugs that cropped
up as the team worked on final edits, and prepped for a 1.0 release and
a soft launch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re starting to ramp up on the Simulating Risk project, and have started implementing
a first simulation, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet closed any issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>11.33&lt;/strong>, based largely on the substantial amount of
work completed on the Lenape Timetree project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Work is on-going on the GeoTaste project, but we&amp;rsquo;re still considering how and if to include it in regular iteration reporting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/06/12/featured-lenapetimetree-desktop-zoom.png"
alt="A screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing new desktop zoom feature, for improved accessibility."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>A screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing new desktop zoom feature, for improved accessibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 8 - May 19, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/05/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/05/22/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/22/featured-lenape-dedication_huf7eb539c7032352e9298967ccbee171f_1733668_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="350"/>
&lt;p>We continue to focus on the Lenape project as we push it towards completion and soft-launch. We implemented the dedication on the tree, and also completed several UI cleanup items and other chores.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/22/featured-lenape-dedication.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing the dedication, which was implemented last iteration."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree project showing the dedication, which was implemented last iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 24 - May 5, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/05/08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/05/08/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/featured-lenapetimetree-zoom_hu3d530068d76b4ed70eefd48719096ea6_895554_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="690"/>
&lt;p>As in recent iterations, we again focused almost exclusively on the Lenape Timetree project, and made significant progress, including: finishing zoom functionality for mobile, drawing lines for the tree branches, adding a branch legend to the intro panel, and implementing content page and footer designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/featured-lenapetimetree-zoom.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing zoom functionality on mobile."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing zoom functionality on mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/lenapetimetree-branches-legend.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing drawn lines for branches and branch legend in the introduction panel."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project showing drawn lines for branches and branch legend in the introduction panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/05/08/lenapetimetree-contentpages.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree About page showing content page styles and visual identity."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree About page showing content page styles and visual identity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2023 Q2 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2023/04/2023-q2-schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/04/2023-q2-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 10 - Apr 21, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/04/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/04/24/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/featured-lenape-timetree-active-tag_huc786050210fdda10bfd2153a5e28147a_503140_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="387"/>
&lt;p>For the second iteration in a row, we were able to focus all of our efforts on the Lenape Timetree project as we work to get it over the finish line, and we made significant progress, completing 27 points and 26 issues across design and development work. On the design side, we finished 18 points and 13 issues for a rolling velocity of 9.7; major efforts included the footer, work on visual identity, and 404 error page designs. On the development side, we closed 9 points and 13 issues, bringing our rolling velocity up to 4. The main functionality completed is a collection of user stories related to tag interactions within the timetree.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/featured-lenape-timetree-active-tag.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project with a tag active, highlighting leaves with that tag and deactivating others"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project with a tag active, highlighting leaves with that tag and deactivating others&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/24/lenape-mobile-info.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project on mobile showing the info button to redisplay the intro when closed"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape timetree project on mobile showing the info button to redisplay the intro when closed&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 27 - Apr 7, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/04/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/04/10/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/10/featured-lenape-timetree-branch-order_hu1309d25c97d49ebdf860bf16651cefd6_539235_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="442"/>
&lt;p>All our effort went towards the Lenape Timetree project as we work to get it over the finish line. There isn&amp;rsquo;t as much visible progress in terms of closed issues as we might hope. Development velocity is &lt;strong>2.3&lt;/strong> with 2 points and 7 issues closed, and design velocity is &lt;strong>7.7&lt;/strong> with 2 issues closed. The development points are low in part to the number of design implementation, which we typically track as chores when they are not easily articulable as user-facing features. We have a large number of issues in progress, which hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to complete early this iteration and get a better estimate of how much work is left.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/04/10/featured-lenape-timetree-branch-order.png"
alt="Screenshot of the latest developmentversion of the Lenape Timetree, showing the leaves organized and more clearly separated by branch"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the &lt;a href="https://lenape-timetree-dev.onrender.com/">latest developmentversion of the Lenape Timetree&lt;/a>, showing the leaves organized and more clearly separated by branch&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 13 - Mar 24, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/03/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/03/27/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/27/featured-lenape-timetree-visual-debug_hue534a4a08b2103be603548c3311a58ab_433041_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="487"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we were able to focus entirely on the Lenape Timetree project. We continued with significant progress on the design work. On the implementation side, we made progress on network layout adjustments, a new visual debug mode to help understand and improve the layout, and some visual cleanup. Design rolling velocity is &lt;strong>11.7&lt;/strong>; development rolling velocity is &lt;strong>5.7&lt;/strong> but only 1 point and 3 development issues were closed, in part due to partial team stafing during the iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/27/featured-lenape-timetree-visual-debug.png"
alt="Screenshot showing Lenape Timetree with visual debug mode turned on"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing Lenape Timetree with visual debug mode turned on&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 27 - Mar 10, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/03/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/03/13/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/13/featured-lenape-active-leaf-style_hucd1111bb7773a1584664ae9e1e561176_810615_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="416"/>
&lt;p>In this iteration, PPA 3.9 was released, which includes a major improvement to search functionality so that similar works or reprints are clustered by default (the relevant functionality was tested and accepted the previous iteration). On the Lenape Timetree project, major design issues were accomplished for tag and leaf interactions. We also completed the first-pass implementation on the active leaf styles, hover interactions for corresponding leaf and labels, and url behavior that makes it possible to bookmark the tree with a specific leaf showing. We also contributed to some small bugfixes and a major indexing speed improvement for the Geniza project — work that was previously left in-progress, and benefited from a recent discovery made while working on PPA that made it possible to optimize the database queries used for bulk indexing (indexing all Geniza documents went from somewhere around 20-30 minutes to ~2 minutes.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity is stable, at &lt;strong>7 points&lt;/strong>, but this is due to the large number of points closed in the previous iteration when we completed the PPA search clustering functionality. We only completed &lt;strong>4 points&lt;/strong> of development work in the current iteration. The design velocity is on an upward trend, with two very productive iterations in a row, reflecting the substantial amount of design progress on the Lenape Timetree project in recent weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/03/13/featured-lenape-active-leaf-style.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree showing active leaf style"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree showing active leaf style&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 13 - Feb 24, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/02/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/27/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/featured-ppa-cluster-on-browse_hu2b2e8c7ec08532430d7ad39a42c4c6fa_252621_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="361"/>
&lt;p>At long last, we finally completed the PPA issues for clustering search results by default, after multiple rounds of testing, and addressing a few regressions introduced by the changes.
A new version of parasolr (0.9) has been released with the needed grouping functionality,
and we expect to release a new version of PPA with the functionality early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the Lenape Timetree project, we&amp;rsquo;ve made tremendous progress on design work for leaves in various states and other interactions, and saw some progress on improving the layout of the tree (multiline labels, adjusted leaf sizes, adjusted sizing for century bands.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the large PPA work that was finally completed, we closed &lt;strong>12&lt;/strong> development points for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>6.67&lt;/strong> — up significantly from preceding iterations, but probably higher than we expect going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/featured-ppa-cluster-on-browse.png"
alt="Screenshot of PPA archive search/browse showing clustered results."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of PPA archive search/browse showing clustered results.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/27/lenape-timetree-multiline-labels.png"
alt="Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project, which now has multiline labels and adjusted leaf sizes."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Lenape Timetree project, which now has multiline labels and adjusted leaf sizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 30 - Feb 10, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/02/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/02/13/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/13/featured-lenape-leaves_hub5256ca78b523dea52a63b5d1b97f5f3_449673_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="504"/>
&lt;p>The only project with issues closed this iteration is the Lenape Princeton Timetree. We made progress on a number of design issues, and completed features to represent the data points as leaves and embed images in leaf details. There was some progress on
PPA to address issues found in testing, but the work was stalled with problems updating the staging site to deliver for retesting. Our rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>3.67&lt;/strong> and holding pretty steady for now around three points.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/02/13/featured-lenape-leaves.png"
alt="Screenshot of current development version of the Lenape Princeton Timetree, showing leaf shapes and latest leaf data"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of current development version of the Lenape Princeton Timetree, showing leaf shapes and latest leaf data&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 16 - Jan 27, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/01/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/30/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/30/featured-lenape-colors-typography_hu265ad66af4bec21e1d4dad9d3a715521_381768_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="398"/>
&lt;p>This iteration, we completed a lot of design and development work on Lenape. We also made progress on PPA, but there is a complicated group of related features that needs a few small changes after the most recent round of testing; we hope to complete those and deliver them to production in the coming iteration. The low development velocity (&lt;strong>3 points&lt;/strong>) is consistent over the last few weeks, but significantly impacted by the amount of team member time spent on teaching for Wintersession and H+DSI.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/30/featured-lenape-colors-typography.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site, with colors and typography implemented"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site, with colors and typography implemented&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Warranty Report: Princeton Geniza Project</title><link>/blog/2023/01/warranty-report-princeton-geniza-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/warranty-report-princeton-geniza-project/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 9 — Jan 13, 2023</title><link>/blog/2023/01/17-january/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:01:02 +0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/17-january/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-january/featured-lenape-tree-labels_hu47de2d5b648f831843d3269aaebd6eb3_376536_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="416"/>
&lt;p>Tracking early January as a short iteration for reporting purposes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made some progress on PPA and Lenape Timetree; we also completed some chores related to Ansible, including the replication playbook that has been in use in draft status for months and a task to update vault passwords due to the recent LastPass breach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also have work nearly complete enabling contractor deploy for Princeton Geniza Project. The issue is not tracked here because the pull request is still under review, but the new setup was used successfully for version 4.12 of Geniza listed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-january/featured-lenape-tree-labels.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site with preliminary labels attached to leaves"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree development site with preliminary labels attached to leaves&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 12 — 23, 2022</title><link>/blog/2023/01/17-december/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 11:01:00 +0500</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/17-december/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-december/featured-lenape-select-leaf_hu5c167c8ca3f1eb09a0f1148309fd88b3_239070_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="417"/>
&lt;p>We fixed a couple of bugs on Princeton Geniza Project and tagged deployed a micro release to get the fixes into production. We also made some progress on the Lenape Timetree project. It isn&amp;rsquo;t reflected in the closed issues listed below, but we did make significant progress on PPA development work; we simply were not able to deliver for testing or close the issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2023/01/17-december/featured-lenape-select-leaf.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree preliminary development site (largely unstyled) showing details for a single selected leaf."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Lenape Timetree preliminary development site (largely unstyled) showing details for a single selected leaf.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Looking back at 2022 — all Geniza, all the time</title><link>/blog/2023/01/looking-back-at-2022-all-geniza-all-the-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/looking-back-at-2022-all-geniza-all-the-time/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The charts below show the substantial amount of effort dedicated to the Princeton Geniza Project in 2022, with a noticeable spike as we worked to complete our commitments on the project before the charter period ended in October.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also noticeable activity on Startwords to finish publication on issue 3; work on PPA enhancements in August and November/December; and beginning to ramp up work on the Lenape Timetree project in the fall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The small amount of work spent on CDH web and mep-django (codebase for Shakepeare and Company Project) reflect a deliberate effort to minimize the work on those projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: What did we work on in 2021?</title><link>/blog/2023/01/what-did-we-work-on-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2023/01/what-did-we-work-on-in-2021/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A belated look back at the work we did in 2021. The substantial effort on CDH web reflects the work to migrate to Wagtail for content management. We completed a substantial amount of work on the Princeton Geniza Project across the whole year, a set of enhancements for PPA in July, and a small amount of work on Startwords to publish issue 2. The work on the derrida-django codebase in the fall was to revise the published datasets and prep the side for archiving.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2023 Q1 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2022/12/2023-q1-schedule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/12/2023-q1-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 28 - Dec 9, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/12/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/12/12/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/12/12/featured_lenape-timetree-leaves-graph_hu051c0535ab9f2a0b46e61fd7cb1923c1_203745_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="333"/>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a busy time of year and we had a lot of other work going on in the past two that impacted what we were able to complete in terms of development and design work. For development, we closed 3 points and 13 issues for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>5.3&lt;/strong> points. Design work is in progress, but none of it was completed since we&amp;rsquo;re still ramping back up on work that was paused.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lenape-timetree">Lenape timetree&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re finally starting to make more progress, including deciding who will review and sign off on development and design work for the project. We completed one story for the algorithmic layout of the leaves in the timetree, and completed some chores that will help set us up to work more efficiently moving forward (visual review with Percy, automated Lighthouse checks for accessibility, SEO, and page efficiency).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Following up on our recent migration, we closed a number of chores and bugs (some of which were resolved by the migration). We didn&amp;rsquo;t complete the major next feature because other commitmennts didn&amp;rsquo;t give us enough time to follow up on tackling something so complex.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed a couple of bug fixes, two of which were introduced in the last release. Hopefully we can release a micro update with those bug fixes and get them out to production soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Note:&lt;/em> starting this iteration, we&amp;rsquo;re adding a new ignored tag, &lt;code>performant&lt;/code>. Issues with this label will be included in the list of closed issues but ignored when summarizing work completed and calculating velocity, since that work is being completed by a contractor and not done by this team.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/12/12/featured_lenape-timetree-leaves-graph.png"
alt="Screenshot of the draft Lenape timetree site showing the leaves algorithmically laid out using a network and d3.js forces"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the draft Lenape timetree site showing the leaves algorithmically laid out using a network and d3.js forces&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 14 - Nov 25, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/11/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/11/28/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/11/28/featured_pgp-metadata-flatviewer_hu8e1fe046dc5df851ef3634891c442444_190567_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="370"/>
&lt;p>We completed a couple of major things before the Thanksgiving holiday — completed the PPA migration to PUL infrastructure, and completed the dataset export work for PGP. We
completed &lt;strong>12&lt;/strong> development points for a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>5.33&lt;/strong> - the low velocity is due to the number of chores required to complete the PPA migration. We also finally completed the charter for the Lenape Timetree project, and will be circulating it to project stakeholders soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-prosody-archive">Princeton Prosody Archive&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed the last few steps for the migration, released version &lt;strong>3.8.1&lt;/strong> and switched the production site over so it is running on PUL infrastructure. We&amp;rsquo;ve already completed some initial upgrades (python version) that are easier to manage now, and are circling back to in-progress that wasn&amp;rsquo;t completed when PPA was in active development in August.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released version &lt;strong>4.11&lt;/strong> with a few search improvements needed to decommission PGPv3 and completed work on dataset exports which will be the basis for published datasets from the project data. We also setup Zenodo sync for the codebase, registering a DOI and adding a citation file to make the code more citable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also have a large number of old issues that were closed thanks to some work from PGP project managers going through and reviewing — some of them have already been addressed, others are duplicates, and others are no longer priorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/11/28/featured_pgp-metadata-flatviewer.png"
alt="Princeton Geniza Project documents data export displayed in Flat GitHub&amp;amp;rsquo;s Flat viewer."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Princeton Geniza Project &lt;a href="https://flatgithub.com/princetongenizalab/pgp-metadata?filename=data%2Fdocuments.csv&amp;amp;sha=549836002cd41abf84e61829439b7b4bf3505af0">documents data export displayed in Flat GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Flat viewer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/11/28/pgp-metadata-commits.png"
alt="Princeton Geniza Project metadata repository showing commit history with co-author information."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Princeton Geniza Project metadata repository showing &lt;a href="https://github.com/princetongenizalab/pgp-metadata/commits/main">commit history with co-author information&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/11/28/pgp-description-bigram-search.png"
alt="Princeton Geniza Project search showing partial word searching on document descriptions."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Princeton Geniza Project search showing &lt;a href="https://geniza.princeton.edu/en/documents/?q=al-fad">partial word searching on document descriptions&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 31 - Nov 11, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/11/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/11/14/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The points completed in the last iteration are low due to staffing
and the fact that our work has been focused on migrations and bug fixes.
Our rolling velocity is &lt;strong>7.3&lt;/strong>, but that may be artificially inflated
by the high point total three iterations ago when we were closing out
the official charter period for the Geniza project.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve made substantial progress on the PPA migration, as evidenced by the
number of closed issues. We&amp;rsquo;ve figured out and resolved several problems,
so now it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of getting everything setup on the new production
server. We&amp;rsquo;re hopeful that we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to complete the migration this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released a hotfix (version 4.10.1) because we discovered a high priority
bug that needed to be corrected quickly. The script that runs as a cron job to
export annotations and transcription content to GitHub for a versioned backup
was broken by a scenario we didn&amp;rsquo;t consider or encounter in testing: deleting
an annotation and then deleting (in this case via merge) the document it belonged to.
We were able to resolve this, along with a fix for a sorting regression in v4.10.
We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on the data export work for dataset publication,
and supporting the project under the CDH warranty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 17 - Oct 28, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/10/31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/10/31/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/10/31/featured-pgp-partialsearch_hu84a8998a02e048c7e2b3a06f1f41117d_271955_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="508"/>
&lt;p>This iteration marked the end of the charter for year 2 of the
CDH Research Partnership on Princeton Geniza Project (PGP). We released version
4.10 of PGP, with some bugfixes and small search and data improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re ramping up on other projects (PPA migration and the Lenape timetree),
but didn&amp;rsquo;t close any issues on those projects in the past iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>15&lt;/strong> but only &lt;strong>3&lt;/strong> development points
for this iteration; we expect velocity to go down now that we&amp;rsquo;re not working on
the Geniza project.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/10/31/featured-pgp-partialsearch.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results showing partial matches and Arabic font##"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results showing partial matches and Arabic font##&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 4 - Oct 15, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/10/18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/10/18/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/10/18/featured_pgp_transcription_editor_hu7d3222f71ef9700af0749bd8c35fcd23_1056625_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="346"/>
&lt;p>Another high point iteration, as we made the final push to finish work
for the CDH/Geniza Research Partnership. For development, we closed &lt;strong>18 points&lt;/strong> across 31 issues, resulting in a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>18.67&lt;/strong> (&lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> the same as last iteration).
Design also had a big push, closing &lt;strong>14 points&lt;/strong> across 9 issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released v4.9 of Princeton Geniza Project mid-iteration. This was a major update
which included the long-awaited transcription migration from TEI to the new W3C
annotation format, and rolled out the new transcription editor tool, annotorious-tahqiq. This includes full functionality needed to add, edit, and delete transcriptions
with support for right-to-left text, as well as a new automated backup that
synchronizes transcription content to a GitHub repository, with co-author commits
to track contributions. As part of this release, we also loaded a number
of new images from Bodleian and JRL collections. After the release went out,
we started tackling bugs with the editor not found in testing and finishing
the remaining committed functionality for the CDH/PGP charter, prioritizing
search improvements for sunsetting PGPv3 and CSV exports for data publication,
with a smaller amount of effort going to localization functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lenape-timetree">Lenape Timetree&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made significant progress on sitemap and wireframe designs for this project,
making a big push to get things ready for development while design is paused
for a month.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/princetongenizalab/pgp-text">PGP transcription export&lt;/a> — browse the transcription content synchronized from the application, in annotation format and compiled into html and text&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/10/18/featured_pgp_transcription_editor.png"
alt="Screenshot of transcription editor on the Princeton Geniza Project site"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of transcription editor on the Princeton Geniza Project site&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/7234006/194160646-e55abbcb-ef27-4482-b204-c19536d28091.gif"
alt="Screen capture showing transcription with tahqiq"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screen capture showing transcription with tahqiq&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 19 - Sep 30, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/10/03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/10/03/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We had a massive iteration, as we make a push to complete the major remaining
deliverables on the Princeton Geniza Project before the partnership grant ends.
We also made some small progress on the Lenape timetree project. We completed
&lt;strong>48&lt;/strong> total points and closed &lt;strong>35&lt;/strong> issues for the Geniza project.
Looking just at development work, we &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> development points across
the same number of issues, and our rolling development velocity is
at &lt;strong>18.7&lt;/strong>. For design, we closed an astounding &lt;strong>25&lt;/strong> points, all on Geniza.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>On the development side, we&amp;rsquo;re making the last push to complete the steps needed to migrate the transcription content and launch the new transcription editor. This included a number of improvements to the editor, as well as the majority of the implementation of the functionality for backing up and versioning transcription content on GitHub. We fixed a bug in the Arabic to Judaeo-Arabic search syntax that was breaking exact phrase searching in Arabic. We also addressed several small accessibility problems that were flagged by the University&amp;rsquo;s new scanning tool, DubBot. For design, work completed
includes Arabic fonts and typography. Design work closed this iteration also includes a number of issues
related to site flow and preliminary designs for the cluster search,
which were designed in a previous iteration (before we decided to postpone that work),
and were reviewed and closed at the beginning of this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We did not release a new version of the PGP site this iteration, but expect to release an update in the first half of this iteration and go live with the transcription migration and editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lenape-timetree">Lenape timetree&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed a task to improve the summary display of imported &amp;ldquo;leaf&amp;rdquo; data; the design work for sitemap and site flow was not yet being tracked in GitHub. Other improvements to the prototype site and design are ongoing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2022 Q4 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2022/09/2022-q4-schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/09/2022-q4-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Sep 5 - Sep 16, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/09/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/09/19/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/09/19/featured-geniza-reorder-images_hubdae640f3fa12ed42074144434d29035_449003_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="352"/>
&lt;p>Our primary focus continues to be Princeton Geniza Project, but we&amp;rsquo;re also
starting to track work on the Lenape Timetree project, and had a few releases
for other projects for maintenance and other updates. We closed &lt;strong>14&lt;/strong> development points and development velocity held nearly steady at &lt;strong>15&lt;/strong> points. We also closed a whopping &lt;strong>11&lt;/strong> design points across 8 issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed work on a feature to allow admins to reorder images for a document, which was released in version 4.8; this caused a bug in editing documents without images, which necessitated a quick bugfix and releasing 4.8.1. We continued to make progress on the transcription migration &amp;amp; editor functionality. On the design side, we closed a number of issues related to the Hebrew version of the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="lenape-princeton-timetree">Lenape Princeton Timetree&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We just started tracking work on this project in GitHub, which at this point consists of preliminary versions of a static site to work and a script to parse existing data,
as a way of prototyping and proposing a data model and site structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other-releases">Other releases&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released a bugfix for the CDH website that was needed to help with freshening the site for thef all semester. We also released PPA version 3.8, with extended Gale/ECCO functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/09/19/featured-geniza-reorder-images.png"
alt="Screenshot showing the Geniza project image re-ordering feature in action"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing the Geniza project image re-ordering feature in action&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/09/19/shxco_footer.png"
alt="Screenshot of revised Shakespeare and Company Project showing the revised footer, which allows for more pages and includes the Project&amp;amp;rsquo;s ISSN"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of revised Shakespeare and Company Project showing the revised footer, which allows for more pages and includes the Project&amp;rsquo;s ISSN&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 23 - Sep 3, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/09/06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/09/06/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/09/06/featured-cdh-affiliates_hu8eabf4e248fc08229aaaa06d513fc504_1088016_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="651"/>
&lt;p>We had another very productive iteration; we had &lt;strong>18&lt;/strong> points total accepted on the Princeton Geniza Project, and we completed &lt;strong>18&lt;/strong> development points. This results in a rolling development velocity of &lt;strong>15.7&lt;/strong> points, continuing our upward trend. We closed a total of 23 development issues, which includes a high number of chores and bugs; some of these were on other projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The high number of points this iteration is largely due to significant progress on the transcription migration and new transcription editor functionality. We did also address some small bugs and other minor fixes; we did not release these changes to production during the iteration because we decided to prioritize other things, including making progress on the transcription editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-website">CDH website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We needed to update the CDH website so that Humanities + Data Science Institute instructors and participants could be included on our affiliates pages. We also corrected a few small bugs and accessibility problems in the process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No development activity, but the remaining issues completed in the previous iteration were accepted. The completed work should be released and deployed early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sco">S&amp;amp;co&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We squeezed in two very minor updates to the Shakespeare and Company site; we hope these also will be released and deployed early this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/09/06/featured-cdh-affiliates.png"
alt="Affiliates page on the CDH website, which now includes Humanities &amp;#43; Data Science Institute instructors and participants"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://cdh.princeton.edu/people/affiliates/">Affiliates page on the CDH website&lt;/a>, which now includes Humanities + Data Science Institute instructors and participants&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Aug 8 - Aug 19, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/08/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/08/22/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/22/featured-geniza-nondocument-image_hu0bea99bbc63d5b21f7df3f8c8e1be338_356321_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="560"/>
&lt;p>We had a productive iteration, making good progress on both Princeton Geniza Project and Princeton Prosody Archive (PPA). We closed &lt;strong>13&lt;/strong> development points (18 issues); with three strong iterations in a row, we&amp;rsquo;re up to a rolling development velocity of &lt;strong>12&lt;/strong> points. We didn&amp;rsquo;t close design issues, but that&amp;rsquo;s because we have larger design tasks in progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released version 4.7, which includes some content editor improvements for tagging; improved display for non-document images in the image+transcription panel viewer for documents; the newly designed light/dark mode toggle was also implemented.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed the remaining work on Gale/ECCO import and support that was leftover from last year&amp;rsquo;s enhancements, in particular: admin import for small batches,
excerpt support for Gale/ECCO works, and data improvements that were delayed pending API changes on Gale&amp;rsquo;s end. We started on functionality to group works into clusters to gather reprints and editions. We also did some other minor updates to improve performance, accessibility, and make the site more consistent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="other">Other&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>updated the Startwords site with fixes for a couple of small display issues&lt;/li>
&lt;li>created a new organization-wide GitHub template for our team software release checklist (previously tracked as a template task in Asana)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/22/featured-geniza-nondocument-image.png"
alt="Screenshot from Princeton Geniza Project showing new display for images that are part of a shelfmark or fragment but not part of the current document"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot from Princeton Geniza Project showing new display for images that are part of a shelfmark or fragment but not part of the current document&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/22/geniza-lightdark-toggle.gif"
alt="Screen capture of Princeton Geniza Project showing light/dark mode toggle in action"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screen capture of Princeton Geniza Project showing light/dark mode toggle in action&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 25 - Aug 5, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/08/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/08/15/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/15/featured-sw3-home-es_hu69c047a2f4fcedf58044d2b58d1f46ce_322226_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="424"/>
&lt;p>Belated iteration report, due to vacations last week. We closed a lot of development work (16 points, 23 issues); this is likely due to the transcription editor functionality that was tested and accepted and the number of small chores in the final push to get Startwords issue 3 out the door.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finally published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/3/">Startwords issue 3&lt;/a>! GitHub issues completed in this iteration were chores related to getting the release out and quick bug fixes to address problems we discovered after the issue was published.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Version 4.6 went into production, with the new image + transcription viewer. We also tested closed a number of features related to the transcription editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ppa">PPA&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We started ramping back up on PPA development work this iteration, beginning with some python package updates and a few small chores.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/08/15/featured-sw3-home-es.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords home page in Spanish with Issue 3 published"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords home page in Spanish with Issue 3 published&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jul 4 - Jul 22, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/07/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/07/25/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/07/25/featured_geniza_itt_huc4dd34ec8528b5941c858b1d744782a9_3118254_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="313"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we completed implementation of the MVP for the new image + transcription viewing panel on the document details page on the Princeton Geniza Project site. Specific features completed include image zoom controls (zoom is no longer enabled by default, which resolves some accessibility problems and avoids making the zoom a scroll trap) and switching between editions when a document has more than one transcription. We also completed work on a revised tag style, a change which was needed to properly handle accessibility checks and making sure that tags are always big enough tap targets. Although we completed the MVP functionality for the new viewer, we were delayed with releasing it to the production site due to a change in the interim transcription format and problems synchronizing transcriptions for documents with more than one edition, which requires data work to resolve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We completed 7 points of development work (10 issues) for a rolling velocity of 9.3; design work was impacted by staff unavailability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/07/25/featured_geniza_itt.png"
alt="Screenshot of the new image and transcription panel interface from the Princeton Geniza Project, showing image zoom controls."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the new image and transcription panel interface from the Princeton Geniza Project, showing image zoom controls.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/07/25/geniza_new_tag.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results with revised tag styles."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search results with revised tag styles.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jun 7 - Jun 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/06/21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/21/featured_geniza_datesortfilter_hu37daa875e16c4aed843a1ec6b98ccb96_93893_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="751"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our primary focus was on Princeton Geniza Project, but we did close a few more issues related to the upcoming Startwords issue 3. Our development velocity is on an upward trend — we closed &lt;strong>21&lt;/strong> development points (16 issues), which gives us a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>13.7&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="princeton-geniza-project">Princeton Geniza Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we released version 4.5, which adds several features related to document date functionality: calendar conversion in admin for simple cases with Anno Mundi and Hijri calendars, improved date display on document details, and sorting and filtering search results by date. We also rolled out the new &amp;ldquo;related documents&amp;rdquo; page, improved image credits display for JTS content, and fixed a bug with handling Heidelberg IIIF. This update required a supporting release of &lt;code>djiffy&lt;/code>, to add support for displaying Creative Commons licenses in addition to rightstatements.org licenses. Several features for the new image+transcription panel viewer were tested but not released; they won&amp;rsquo;t go out until we have a full replacement for the current display, hopefully in the next release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finished work on the new authors list page, adjusted the footer to add a link to the authors page, and completed a few other small style-related changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/21/featured_geniza_datesortfilter.png"
alt="Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search page with document date filter and sort options."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Princeton Geniza Project search page with document date filter and sort options.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/21/startwords-authors.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords author list page."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords author list page.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: May 23 - Jun 3, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/06/06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/06/06/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/06/featured_startwords-textshadows_hueb450c0ae95931c0a7535cfca2ce0352_362871_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="544"/>
&lt;p>We adjusted the schedule to make the past iteration a three-week iteration due to the Memorial holiday resulting in a very short week. Due to holidays, team member availability, and the chunks of work that are in progress, we didn&amp;rsquo;t publish any releases, but we did complete a lot of work. Our development velocity is up to &lt;strong>9.3&lt;/strong> points (14 points, 21 issues). We have the same exact velocity for design work (&lt;strong>9.3&lt;/strong>), with 12 points and 7 issues closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Major design work closed related to the new image and transcription panel, for which implementation are underway. We also completed designs for the related documents page. We also finished work on a number of features related to date filtering and historical calendar conversion, which we hope to make available in production soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed much of the remaining work needed for issue 3, including: revised shadow text styles for the site homepage and single issue pages (pictured below), generalized the interlude styles invented for SW issue 1 so it can be used in any article in future; improved DOI display for translated articles; and fixed a couple of bugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cdh-ansible">cdh-ansible&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A small improvement in our project deploy scripts, suggested by PUL staff, resulted in a huge improvement in the time it takes to deploy projects, by configuring the deploy scripts to skip one-time setup tasks by default.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/06/06/featured_startwords-textshadows.png"
alt="Screenshot of the development version of Startwords showing the newly redesigned and reimplemented text shadows and three-feature essay layout."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the development version of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> showing the newly redesigned and reimplemented text shadows and three-feature essay layout.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2022 Q3 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2022/05/2022-q3-schedule/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/2022-q3-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: May 2 - May 13, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/05/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/16/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We released Geniza v4.4 early in this iteration to deliver work completed in the previous iteration, and then quickly discovered and fixed a bug with the menu button that made the site unnavigable on mobile. We did not get another release out during the iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made progress on a number of design and development issues and both rolling velocity and iteration development work are at &lt;strong>6 points&lt;/strong>. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t reflect the large amount of in-progress work on transcription functionality (delivered for first-round testing but still very much in progress) and several related features around date/calendar conversion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>No development work this iteration, but design work for issue 3 is nearly complete and editorial and design work will be ready soon for final handoff for development on the remaining items needed for completing this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 18 - Apr 29, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/05/02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/05/02/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/05/02/featured-geniza-doc-details_hu6e508823ce402b666b0a6fbd9a76aa08_128232_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="528"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made progress on Geniza and closed out several issues for Startwords. We weren&amp;rsquo;t able to get a release out with the Geniza updates due to team commitments and availability at the end of the iteration, but we hope to get a release out early this iteration with the completed work. Our development velocity is fairly steady at &lt;strong>5&lt;/strong> points, but we closed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> development points and &lt;strong>17&lt;/strong> issues. We&amp;rsquo;re also continuing to make good progress with design work on both projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Notable work includes improvements to the public search — a filter for documents with images, options to sort by input date and shelfmark, and our first foray into Judaeo-Arabic conversion, making it possible to search on Judaeo-Arabic transcription content when inputting Arabic search terms. We updated the admin document view so that it uses the same image and transcription viewer as the public site, and improved the display and functionality in the IIIF image rights in that section. We also made progress on RTL design implementations, resolved a long-standing font loading issue in Percy, and finally set up Sphinx code documentation. We&amp;rsquo;re continuing to make progress on design and development for the new transcription functionality, although we have not yet been able to deliver it for testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We finalized designs for the new author list and linking to the author page in the footer, and completed testing on issues for reading articles and issues in translation and toggling between languages. We delivered a draft version of Issue 3 to the contributors with their revisions, so we are getting closer to publishing this issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/05/02/featured-geniza-doc-details.png"
alt="Screenshot of revised document details page"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of revised document details page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/05/02/geniza-sort-options.png"
alt="Screenshot of document search with new sorts and filters"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of document search with new sorts and filters&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/05/02/geniza-image-rights.png"
alt="Screenshot of revised image rights and permalink on document details page"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of revised image rights and permalink on document details page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2022 Q2 Schedule</title><link>/blog/2022/04/2022-q2-schedule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 11:54:48 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/2022-q2-schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blog: Apr 5 - Apr 16, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/04/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/18/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/18/featured-startwords-multilingual_hu323df8a84995277b79811538ff69610f_256815_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="382"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we made progress on the remaining multilingual functionality and other features needed to publish &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> issue 3. We didn&amp;rsquo;t close a lot of points on the Geniza project because the major work going on at this point is prototyping and beginning to implement the new transcription functionality, and sketching out design ideas for the public display and interaction of images with transcription and translation content. Our rolling development velocity is &lt;strong>4.67&lt;/strong>, due to the low number of points completed in the last two iterations (3, 4). We expect this to pick up once we move out of the transcription prototyping phase and finish work on the Startwords issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/18/featured-startwords-multilingual.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords development site with multilingual functionality: translated navigation and paratext, available language indicators"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of Startwords development site with multilingual functionality: translated navigation and paratext, available language indicators&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 21 - Apr 1, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/04/04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/04/04/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/04/featured-startwords-issue-langs_hu4c7ef2aa063be4f046914b1e883493b9_94528_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="347"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we worked on needed functionality for &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> Issue 3, and made more progress prototyping and testing functionality for a transcription solution for the Geniza project. Because much of the development work consisted of chores, exploratory or prototyping, our iteration velocity and rolling velocity are both fairly low. We did make significant progress with Design work, both for Geniza and Startwords.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/04/04/featured-startwords-issue-langs.png"
alt="Screenshot of Startwords issue list, which now includes indicators for available languages."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> issue list, which now includes indicators for available languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Published new &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em> documentation pages: &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/guides/editorial-guidelines/">Editorial Guidelines&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/guides/style-guide/">Contributor Style Guide&lt;/a> (both linked from the About page)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://pgp-transcription-prototype.glitch.me/">Geniza transcription experiments and prototypes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Blog: Mar 7 - Mar 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/03/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/21/featured-document-detail_hu887688024267b446f1b1936aa274aecc_84252_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="777"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our focus again was solely on the Geniza project. We put out a bug-fix release early in the iteration to address several highly noticeable problems that were identified by various members of the team, and then a feature release with new functionality, most notably implementing Turbo and Stimulus to make the document search more responsive and load changes more quickly. We also made some small changes to the document details page, including displaying primary and secondary languages, linking to other documents on the same fragments, and moving secondary metadata lower on the page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our development rolling velocity is steady at &lt;strong>13 points&lt;/strong>, although this iteration we only closed &lt;strong>7&lt;/strong> story points. However, that&amp;rsquo;s in line with what we should expect, since it was effectively a half iteration in terms of developer staffing.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/21/featured-document-detail.png"
alt="Updates to document details page, including language, links to other documents on the same fragments, and secondary metadata made less prominent."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Updates to document details page, including language, links to other documents on the same fragments, and secondary metadata made less prominent.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 21 - Mar 4, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/03/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/03/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/07/featured-geniza-filters_hu56b64b3cea7385267f391b2335cd3a21_670917_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="347"/>
&lt;p>This iteration we were primarily focused on Geniza, but did devote some efforts towards Startwords. Our development velocity has stabilized a bit: 13 points, 20 issues, for a rolling velocity of 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released another update (version 4.2) with more new features and improvements to the public site. The most visible change is the filter panel on the &lt;a href="https://geniza.princeton.edu/en/documents/">document search&lt;/a>, which now includes three new filters related to scholarship records. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on designs and backend support for the RTL versions of the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This iteration we made some small progress on design and infrastructure updates needed for Issue 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/07/featured-geniza-filters.png"
alt="Geniza search filters expanded on desktop, with one selected."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search filters expanded on desktop, with one selected.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/07/geniza-active-filter-icon.png"
alt="Geniza active filter icon, to indicate when search filters are applied."/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza active filter icon, to indicate when search filters are applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/03/07/geniza-favicon.png"
alt="Geniza browser tab &amp;amp;amp; bookmark icon"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza browser tab &amp;amp; bookmark icon&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Feb 7 - Feb 18, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/02/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/02/21/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/21/featured-pgp-logotype_huee92df934de27e87a094628979144288_497057_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="407"/>
&lt;p>This iteration our focus was entirely on the Princeton Geniza Project as we worked to address issues identified in the 4.0 release that we wanted to address before switching the site to the official &lt;a href="https://geniza.princeton.edu">https://geniza.princeton.edu&lt;/a> url (which we did on Thursday!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notable work completed in this iteration includes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>completion of design work on the new logo and logotype (shown below), which will be integrated into the site this week.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>search results now include image thumbnails when available&lt;/li>
&lt;li>an admin document merge function, so that duplicate documents and joins can be merged manually in the admin site instead of relying on spreadsheets and script to handle merging (we discovered the script method was error-prone since merging needs to be done carefully).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Our rolling velocity for development is &lt;strong>13&lt;/strong> points; this iteration we completed 19 points (16 issues).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/21/featured-pgp-logotype.png"
alt="Completed designs for new PGP logo and logotype"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Completed designs for new PGP logo and logotype&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/21/pgp-search-images.png"
alt="Screenshot showing PGP search results with image thumbnails"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot showing PGP search results with image thumbnails&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 24 - Feb 4, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/02/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/02/07/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/07/featured-404-error_hu94ac8d84e3dc675b803d8c1cbeabc3e1_600221_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="493"/>
&lt;p>At long last, we tagged and released the 4.0 version of Princeton Geniza Project! This is meets our agreement for a &amp;ldquo;Minimum Viable Product&amp;rdquo; to replace the current PGP v3.0. The new site isn&amp;rsquo;t publicly available just yet, but we&amp;rsquo;re planning to turn off IP access restriction by Thursday of this week at the latest and hoping to switch it to the official URL within another week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We closed &lt;strong>24&lt;/strong> development issues this iteration, but only completed &lt;strong>8&lt;/strong> story points — likely because much of our focus was on finishing implementing visual designs, fixing bugs, and finishing chores in preparation for this release. Our rolling development velocity is 20 points, due to the huge iteration in December and the fact that we&amp;rsquo;re no longer counting the zero-point iteration around Thanksgiving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The mep-django releases were related to publication of the 1.2 version of the Shakespeare and Company Project datasets, which were published on Princeton&amp;rsquo;s DataSpace on January 31st.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/07/featured-404-error.png"
alt="Geniza 404 Not Found error page"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza 404 Not Found error page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/07/500-error.png"
alt="Geniza 500 Server Error page"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza 500 Server Error page&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/02/07/credits.png"
alt="Geniza credits page, showing content page styles"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza credits page, showing content page styles&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Jan 17 - Jan 28, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/01/31/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/31/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/01/31/featured-geniza-search_hu7216f1b6a544a4d2818a5a27908e21fd_224478_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="440"/>
&lt;p>Belated report on the first iteration of January 2022. This was effectively a long iteration, since it included work completed during the week of January 17th, which was a scheduled R&amp;amp;D week for CDH staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our focus continues to be exclusively on Geniza, as we work closer and closer to completing the initial MVP that will be made public. We made tremendous progress on completing design work for site visuals, implementing the designs, finishing some of the final remaining functionality, and resolving a number of small bugs and chores that needed to be addressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We closed 21 development issues, for a total of 11 story points and a rolling velocity of 17.3.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2022/01/31/featured-geniza-search.png"
alt="Geniza search page, showing the implementation of new site visuals and colors"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Geniza search page, showing the implementation of new site visuals and colors&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item><item><title>Blog: Dec 6 - Dec 31, 2022</title><link>/blog/2022/01/04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2022/01/04/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We extend this iteration to four weeks, which included the Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s holidays
when most of the team was out. During this iteration, we published &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/2/">the second issue of &lt;em>Startwords&lt;/em>&lt;/a> and made significant progress on the Geniza 4.0 release. We have an enormous total of &lt;strong>41&lt;/strong> development story points closed this iteration and a rolling velocity of &lt;strong>18&lt;/strong> — this is due in part to the lengthened iteration, but also due to the significant push to complete the Geniza MVP and closing out a number of large issues (three 8-point development issues and two 5s!). We also have a huge total of &lt;strong>37&lt;/strong> points (16 issues) for design work, completing the majority of the design work for the Geniza MVP. The unevenness of the design velocity likely reflects Gissoo&amp;rsquo;s observation that visual design does not fit well with an Agile development workflow, since so many things need to be designed and reviewed together.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed the remaining work to publish &lt;a href="https://startwords.cdh.princeton.edu/issues/2/">Startwords Issue 2&lt;/a>; work in this iteration included miscellaneous cleanup items for final publication of the essays in issue 2, and some minor cleanup work after the publication. We also started on prep work for functionality needed for issue 3, but none of those issues were closed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Although we postponed the 4.0 public MVP release until January, we did make a significant amount of progress towards completing the work targeted for that MVP, and we did release a 0.7 version with a significant number of updates since the previous release. Updates include improved citation formatting for footnotes and sources, revised scholarship record view for individual documents, an import of data from the PGP v3 links database (information now included in PGP v4 scholarship records), setting up Wagtail for management of content pages, and progress with interim transcription solution for synchronization from TEI to the database, including in search results, and displaying with or without images on document detail pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also made tremendous progress on design: nearly all of the design work needed for the MVP has been completed and approved, and a significant amount of work was done towards implementing site visuals implement them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New versions of djiffy and parasolr were released in support of the Geniza 0.7 release, with support for newer versions of Python &amp;amp; Django and improved functionality needed for the new Geniza search.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: 2022 Q1 schedule</title><link>/blog/2021/12/2022-q1-schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/12/2022-q1-schedule/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Development schedule for first quarter of 2022.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 22 - Dec 3, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/12/06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/12/06/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We made progress on multiple projects, but didn&amp;rsquo;t close anything with points; this is due to the Thanksgiving holiday and the shift to working on Startwords to prep issue 2 for publication.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">Startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We completed a number of updates in preparation for publishing Startwords issue 2, which looks to be in good shape to go out on time as planned.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">Geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The issues closed largely related to design and design implementation. We do have a large issue in-progress and nearly complete to update the scholarship details for individual documents; this issue was larger than expected due to the need to format references more like a citation, which involved some data model changes. Due to the holidays and rolling work on the MVP, we have not made any releases in a while to update production with the latest changes; we probably should do this sometime soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="shakespeare-and-company-project">Shakespeare and Company Project&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We released a micro update with maintenance updates, including python package upgrades and two minor adjustments in support of publishing new versions of the datasets. While we made the update, we added Zenode metadata and a citation file to make the GitHub repository more citable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="archiving-derridas-margins">Archiving Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This work is still not complete, but we made a small amount of progress on the final configuration needed for the archive site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Nov 8 - Nov 19, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/11/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/11/22/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity after this iteration is picking up (7.8) as geniza work gains momentum. For development work, we completed 21 issues and 13 points. We made what we hope to be the final Derrida release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We made progress on the public document search, implementing styles and typography, and a preliminary implementation for synchronizing TEI transcriptions for search and display on the new site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derrida">derrida&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We developed a custom driver for browsertrix-crawler so that we could archive the historgram visualization pages and the deep-zoom image content on the site.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blog: Oct 25 - Nov 5, 2021</title><link>/blog/2021/11/08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2021/11/08/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/11/08/featured-geniza-kwic_hu183aa54baf7030e3cd19aa3fb2aea662_57198_640x0_resize_catmullrom_3.png" width="640" height="355"/>
&lt;p>Our rolling development velocity after this iteration is low (only &lt;strong>4 points&lt;/strong>), but we&amp;rsquo;re starting to gain momentum on the geniza development work and we&amp;rsquo;rec lose to wrapping up maintenance and chore work. For development work, we completed 17 issues and 9 points; we also made progress on geniza design work this iteration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="geniza">geniza&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re starting to make progress on the public site features planned for the first public release (PGP v4.0): adding functionality to the public document search, document details, implementing styles, and working to use localization and internationalization consistently. We&amp;rsquo;re also making progress on visual design and typography.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="derrida">derrida&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the work to archive Derrida&amp;rsquo;s Margins, we completed the remaining work to complete the web archiving (which included a custom web driver to capture the visualization and deep zoom images), and gathered needed information for customizing and configuring the deployed archive site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="startwords">startwords&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Startwords is not scheduled for active development until next iteration, but as we identified and addressed one small item that was determined to be helpful for editing and publication prep; in this case, so the editors could give contributors a preview of how their revised essay might be presented on the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="demos">Demos&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/blog/2021/11/08/featured-geniza-kwic.png"
alt="Screenshot of the Geniza search interface showing matching search terms in context in the document description"/> &lt;figcaption>
&lt;p>Screenshot of the Geniza search interface showing matching search terms in context in the document description&lt;/p>
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description></item></channel></rss>